<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CalmFlight</string>

    <!-- General -->
    <string name="previous">Previous</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="continue_btn">Continue</string>
    <string name="finish_btn">Finish</string>
    <string name="close_btn">Close</string>
    <string name="start_flight_btn">Start Flight</string>
    <string name="end_flight_btn">End Flight</string>
    <string name="cancel_btn">Cancel</string>

    <!-- Flight Mode Dialogs -->
    <string name="flight_start_title">Your flight is about to start</string>
    <string name="flight_start_question">How bad/scary do you expect it to be?</string>
    <string name="flight_end_title">Welcome back!</string>
    <string name="flight_end_question">You are about to end the flight. How bad/scary was the flight actually?</string>
    <string name="flight_mode_active">Flight Mode Active</string>
    <string name="flight_mode_inactive">Start Flight Mode</string>

    <!-- Navigation -->
    <string name="nav_cockpit">Cockpit</string>
    <string name="nav_learn">Learn</string>
    <string name="nav_sos">SOS</string>
    <string name="nav_tools">Tools</string>

    <!-- Cockpit Screen -->
    <string name="cockpit_title">Cockpit</string>
    <string name="g_force_monitor">G-FORCE MONITOR</string>
    <string name="safe_operating_zone">Safe Zone</string>
    <string name="perfectly_safe">You are perfectly safe.</string>
    <string name="immediate_intervention">IMMEDIATE INTERVENTION</string>
    <string name="breathe_with_me_desc">Breathe with me.\nInhale... Exhale...</string>
    <string name="all_systems_normal">All systems\nnormal.</string>
    <string name="cruising_smoothly">We are cruising smoothly.\nFlight deck is calm.</string>
    <string name="calm_flight_desc">Calm flight</string>
    
    <!-- Cockpit Phases Content -->
    <string name="boarding_title">Getting Ready</string>
    <string name="boarding_desc">The anticipation is often worse than the flight itself. Use these tools to quiet your mind before takeoff.</string>
    <string name="takeoff_tools_title">Takeoff Tools</string>
    <string name="cruise_tools_title">Cruise Tools</string>
    <string name="landing_tools_title">Landing Tools</string>
    <string name="tool_shortcut_desc_ptw">Schedule your worry for later instead of fighting it now.</string>
    <string name="tool_shortcut_desc_wo">Exaggerate your fears until they become ridiculous.</string>
    <string name="tool_shortcut_desc_rtw">Feeling panic rising? Ride the adrenaline wave.</string>
    <string name="tool_shortcut_desc_rtw_landing">Handle descent sensations and bumps.</string>
    <string name="tool_shortcut_desc_ftf">Examine your sensations with curiosity.</string>

    <!-- Weather Widget -->
    <string name="weather_widget_title">Flight Conditions</string>
    <string name="weather_check_btn">Check Local Weather</string>
    <string name="weather_permission_hint">Grant location access to see takeoff conditions.</string>
    <string name="weather_loading">Loading weather data...</string>
    <string name="weather_error_generic">Could not load weather data.</string>
    <string name="weather_error_offline">No internet connection. You might be in Flight Mode already!</string>
    <string name="weather_offline_reassurance">Don\'t worry. Pilots have the latest weather data directly in the cockpit.</string>
    <string name="weather_wind_fmt">Wind: %.1f km/h</string>
    <string name="weather_msg_excellent">Conditions are excellent. Expect a smooth takeoff.</string>
    <string name="weather_msg_breezy">It\'s a bit breezy (%.1f km/h). You might feel some bumps, but it\'s completely safe.</string>
    <string name="weather_msg_cloudy">It\'s cloudy or raining. The takeoff might be a little bumpy, but pilots do this every day.</string>

    <!-- G-Force Monitor -->
    <string name="status_smooth">SMOOTH FLIGHT</string>
    <string name="status_light_bumps">LIGHT BUMPS</string>
    <string name="status_moderate">MODERATE CHOP</string>
    <string name="status_bumpy">BUMPY (SAFE)</string>
    <string name="gforce_explanation_title">About this Monitor</string>
    <string name="gforce_explanation">This tool uses your phone\'s accelerometer to measure real-time G-Forces. Commercial planes are built to withstand extreme forces (-1.0G to +2.5G), far beyond what you experience in even the worst turbulence.\n\nPlace your phone flat on a tray table or armrest for best results.</string>
    <string name="gforce_safe_range">Normal Safe Range: -1.0G - 2.5G</string>
    <string name="gforce_current_label">Current</string>
    <string name="gforce_min_label">Min</string>
    <string name="gforce_max_label">Max</string>

    <!-- Flight Status -->
    <string name="status_on_land">On Land</string>
    <string name="status_boarding">Boarding</string>
    <string name="status_takeoff">Takeoff</string>
    <string name="status_cruise">Cruise</string>
    <string name="status_turbulence">Turbulence</string>
    <string name="status_landing">Landing</string>

    <!-- On Land Widget -->
    <string name="on_land_card_title">Ready to fly?</string>
    <string name="on_land_card_desc">Tap the button below to start Flight Mode. You can log your anxiety levels before and after the flight to track your progress.</string>
    <string name="on_land_card_title_active">Flight Mode Active</string>
    <string name="on_land_card_desc_active">Don\'t forget to stop Flight Mode after touchdown! Tap the button below to rate your actual anxiety so you can compare it with your pre-flight expectations and track your progress.</string>

    <!-- Learn Screen -->
    <string name="search_questions">Search questions...</string>
    <string name="search_desc">Search</string>

    <!-- SOS Screen -->
    <string name="pause_and_listen">PAUSE &amp; LISTEN</string>
    <string name="pilot_voice_msg">Pilot Voice: \"You are safe. The plane is flying normally. Focus on your feet...\"</string>
    <string name="exit_sos_mode">EXIT SOS MODE</string>
    <string name="breathe_in">Breathe In</string>
    <string name="hold">Hold</string>
    <string name="breathe_out">Breathe Out</string>
    
    <!-- New SOS Content -->
    <string name="sos_panic_title">I\'M PANICKING\nRIGHT NOW</string>
    <string name="sos_panic_subtitle">My body is shaking or I can\'t breathe</string>
    <string name="sos_turbulence_title">THE PLANE IS\nSCARING ME</string>
    <string name="sos_turbulence_subtitle">It\'s bumpy, noisy, or feels wrong</string>
    <string name="sos_help_message">What is happening right now?</string>

    <!-- Tools Screen -->
    <string name="tools_title">Tools</string>

    <!-- Riding The Wave Tool -->
    <string name="rtw_title">Riding the Wave</string>
    <string name="rtw_intro">You\'re having a panic attack right now and thinking \"Why should I trust this method?\". Here\'s why you can trust it: every panic attack you\'ve ever had - even the ones where you were 100% sure you were dying - ended all by itself.\n\nThat\'s because panic is a surge of adrenaline, and your body simply cannot keep pumping it out forever. It always runs out of fuel and the attack stops, usually within 4-10 minutes at most.\n\n\"Riding the wave\" is one of the main skills taught in Dialectical Behavior Therapy (DBT), a treatment used in hospitals and clinics all over the world for intense panic and emotions. People who learn to stop fighting the feelings finish their panic attacks much faster - often in half the time or less - and have fewer attacks overall.\n\nFighting the wave (\"Make it stop!\") keeps it going for 20-40 minutes. Letting it rise and fall turns it into a 3-5 minute rough patch instead. This isn\'t wishful thinking; it\'s how your body actually works, and thousands of people just like you have proved it.\n\nYou\'re about to prove it too.\n\nBefore we start: Rate your anxiety RIGHT NOW using the slider below. At the end, you\'ll rate it again to see if it helped.</string>
    
    <string name="rtw_step_1">Your heart is pounding. Your chest feels tight. You feel dizzy or unreal. That\'s okay. This is just a wave of adrenaline - it feels awful, but it CANNOT hurt you and it ALWAYS ends. Every single panic attack you\'ve ever had has stopped on its own. This one will too - faster if you stop fighting it.</string>
    <string name="rtw_step_2">Right now, put your phone down for a second and say inside your head:\n\n\"Okay, here it comes. It\'s just the wave.\"</string>
    <string name="rtw_step_3">Don\'t try to slow your breathing. Don\'t try to calm down. Don\'t fight any feeling. Let your heart race as fast as it wants. Let your hands shake. Let the dizziness be there. You are allowing everything to happen exactly as it is.</string>
    <string name="rtw_step_4">Silently tell your body:\n\n\"Go ahead - do your worst. I\'m not going to stop you.\"</string>
    <string name="rtw_step_5">Notice where you feel it most - chest, stomach, throat? Just watch it like you\'re watching a wave at the beach. You don\'t have to like it, you only have to let it be there.</string>
    <string name="rtw_step_6">Keep watching. In a moment you\'ll feel the first tiny drop - maybe your shoulders loosen a bit or the tightness eases just a little. That\'s the wave starting to crash.</string>
    <string name="rtw_step_7">Stay with it. The peak is passing right now. It\'s already going down, even if it doesn\'t feel calm yet.</string>
    <string name="rtw_step_8">You\'re doing it. You\'re riding it instead of drowning in it. A few more breaths and it will keep falling.</string>
    <string name="rtw_step_9">There... feel that? It\'s getting smaller. You\'re safe. The wave is leaving all by itself - because you let it.</string>
    <string name="rtw_step_10">You did it. It\'s over much sooner than if you had fought.\n\nNext time it will be even shorter. You\'ve just proved you can ride any wave.\n\nNow rate your anxiety again using the slider below. Compare it to your initial rating - did it drop? That\'s the proof that riding the wave works.</string>

    <!-- Postpone The Worry Tool -->
    <string name="ptw_title">Postpone the Worry</string>
    <string name="ptw_intro">You\'re thinking: \"Just delay it? That can\'t possibly work.\" It feels too simple, but it\'s one of the most powerful tools in Metacognitive Therapy, the treatment that has been shown in research to reduce anxiety faster and more lastingly than traditional methods.\n\nYour brain treats every scary thought as an urgent problem that must be solved immediately. In a plane, that\'s useless: there is nothing you can do about the wings or the engines right now. Keeping the worry running for hours only exhausts you.\n\nThe trick is to give the worry an official, specific time later - so your mind accepts that the job is safely scheduled and stops pressing the alarm button.</string>
    
    <string name="ptw_step_1">Do this right now:\n\nSay to yourself (quietly or in your head):\n\n\"All worrying and what-if thoughts about the flight are now officially postponed until the very last minute of this flight, just before we land.\"</string>
    <string name="ptw_step_2">Whenever another scary thought appears, answer it with the exact same sentence:\n\n\"Thank you. Postponed until the final minute.\"</string>
    <string name="ptw_step_3">That\'s all. No fighting, no arguing, no reassuring yourself the plane is safe. Just postpone.</string>
    <string name="ptw_step_4">Most people notice the pressure drop within 30-60 seconds because the brain no longer believes the worry is needed right now.</string>
    <string name="ptw_step_5">And here\'s what almost always happens: when that final minute actually arrives hours later, you\'ll look up and realise the worry feels tiny - or you won\'t even remember what you were going to worry about.</string>
    <string name="ptw_step_6">Either way, you will have given yourself hours of calm instead of hours of torment.\n\nPostpone it. You haven\'t lost anything, and you\'ve just reclaimed the rest of your flight.</string>

    <!-- Worry Olympics Tool -->
    <string name="wo_title">Worry Olympics</string>
    <string name="wo_intro">Therapists use this exact method because when you try - with total commitment - to scare yourself even worse on purpose, your brain almost always goes \"Wait... this is ridiculous\" and the panic collapses into laughter or relief in seconds.\n\nDo it right now. Follow every step exactly:</string>
    
    <string name="wo_step_1">Step 1: What You\'re Actually Thinking Right Now\n\nClose your eyes. Don\'t fight it-lean into it. Mentally catalogue the \"evidence\" your anxiety is presenting:\n\n\"That rattle is new. We just dropped 200 feet, I felt it. The wing is bending way too much. Pilot hasn\'t spoken in 8 minutes-he\'s either dead or too busy fighting the controls to talk. Flight attendant smiled too wide; that\'s reassurance masking panic. I should have driven.\"</string>
    <string name="wo_step_2">Step 2: Give Your Fear the Microphone\n\nImagine standing up, grabbing the intercom, and delivering-dead serious-what your nervous system is screaming:\n\n\"Ladies and gentlemen, passenger in 22B. I have updates. That vibration is not normal turbulence; it\'s a harmonic imbalance in the port engine. The wing is flexing beyond manufacturer specs-I\'ve been watching it. The pilot\'s silence is now at 11 minutes, which in aviation time is roughly forever. Also, the coffee tasted off, which is probably hydraulic fluid contamination. I have no formal flight training, but I\'ve consumed every air crash investigation documentary ever made, and I am qualified to say: we should be panicking. Please panic in an orderly fashion.\"</string>
    <string name="wo_step_3">Step 3: What Passengers Are Actually Thinking\n\nLook around.\n\nThe guy next to you: \"Did I close the garage door?\"\n\nThe woman across the aisle: \"Why is the Wi-Fi $8 for 30 minutes? This is theft.\"\n\nKid behind you: \"My iPad is at 3% and this plane has no outlets. My life is over.\"\n\nFlight attendant: \"If one more person asks me about the chicken or pasta option, I\'m quitting.\"</string>
    <string name="wo_step_4">Step 4: Abruptly Yell \"CUT!\"\n\nOpen your eyes. Same engine hum. Same wing flex. Same plane. The only thing that crashed was the story you were telling yourself-because once you voiced it aloud (even just mentally), your brain heard how absurd it sounds.</string>
    <string name="wo_step_5">What Just Happened?\n\nYou caught the fear red-handed, scripting the disaster. You were the narrator, not the passenger. And narrators can change the channel.</string>

    <!-- Facing The Fear Tool -->
    <string name="ftf_title">Facing the Fear</string>
    <string name="ftf_intro">For right now, when the panic feels huge and solid.\n\nSit back, keep your eyes open or closed-whatever feels okay.\n\nWe\'re going to fly straight into the middle of this scary feeling, like a pilot flying into a dark cloud that looks terrifying from far away. Everyone knows that when the plane actually enters the cloud, there\'s nothing there-just soft mist. Let\'s do the same with this emotion.</string>
    
    <string name="ftf_step_1">Start by noticing the feeling as a whole. From a little distance it looks black, heavy, dangerous. That\'s normal. Now we\'re going to get closer, the way a scientist would, curious instead of scared.\n\nFind the strongest part of the feeling right now. Where is it exactly?\n\nMaybe a tight band around your chest, or pressure in your throat, or a swirling in your stomach. Put your attention gently on that spot. Don\'t push it away-just look.</string>
    <string name="ftf_step_2">Ask the feeling, quietly: \"Where are your edges?\"\n\nClouds always look solid from afar, but up close they have no hard border. Is this feeling sharp and solid, or is it actually fuzzy, changing, moving the moment you try to grab it?</string>
    <string name="ftf_step_3">Notice your heart beating fast.\n\nWhen you run for the bus or go up the stairs quickly, your heart races even harder than this-and you don\'t mind at all. What\'s the difference right now?\n\nOnly the story that says \"fast heart = danger.\" Without that story, it\'s just a heart doing its job.</string>
    <string name="ftf_step_4">Now zoom in even closer, like putting the feeling under a microscope.\n\nIs the tightness in your chest actually painful, or is it just pressure?\n\nIs the dizziness really the world spinning, or is it a light, floaty sensation with a scary label stuck on it?</string>
    <string name="ftf_step_5">Keep breathing normally and ask: \"If I didn\'t call this feeling \'panic,\' what would it be?\"\n\nA warm wave? Energy moving? A tingling?\n\nMost people discover it\'s just ordinary body sensations wearing a monster mask.</string>
    <string name="ftf_step_6">Look for the scariest part again. Where did it go?\n\nThe closer you get, the more it dissolves. Just like a real cloud-there\'s no dark centre, no monster hiding inside. Only soft, passing mist.</string>
    <string name="ftf_step_7">Stay here for a few more breaths.\n\nNothing to fix, nothing to fight. You\'re flying right through the middle of the cloud and discovering there was never anything solid to crash into.</string>
    <string name="ftf_step_8">When you\'re ready, open your eyes or soften your gaze.\n\nThe feeling may still be around, but you\'ve seen the truth: it\'s made of the same harmless stuff as every other sensation-just clouds passing through an open sky.\n\nYou can always fly into any cloud and find the same thing: nothing there.</string>

    <string name="anxiety_level_label">Anxiety Level: %d/10</string>
    <string name="rate_btn">Rate</string>
    <string name="feedback_improving">It is getting better! Keep going.</string>
    <string name="feedback_worsening">Trust the process. It will pass.</string>
    <string name="feedback_steady">You are doing great. Ride the wave.</string>
    
    <string name="congrats_title">Well Done!</string>
    <string name="congrats_msg">You managed your panic attack successfully. Every time you ride the wave, it gets easier.</string>

    <!-- Reality Check Tool -->
    <string name="rc_title">Reality Check</string>
    <string name="rc_empty_title">No Flight Data Yet</string>
    <string name="rc_empty_desc">Complete a flight in Flight Mode to see your anxiety tracking here.</string>
    <string name="rc_flight_history">Flight History</string>
    <string name="rc_legend_expected">Expected Fear</string>
    <string name="rc_legend_actual">Actual Reality</string>

    <string name="rc_insight_strong_title">You Are Stronger Than You Think</string>
    <string name="rc_insight_strong_msg">The data proves it: You consistently expect the worst, but your actual experience is much calmer. Your anxiety is lying to you about the danger.</string>

    <string name="rc_insight_surprised_title">Pleasantly Surprised</string>
    <string name="rc_insight_surprised_msg">You tend to brace for a rough ride, but reality is usually kinder. Over time, this gap should get smaller as you learn to trust the plane.</string>

    <string name="rc_insight_realistic_title">Realistic Expectations</string>
    <string name="rc_insight_realistic_msg">Your predictions are quite accurate. You have a grounded view of flying and aren\'t letting catastrophic thoughts take over.</string>

    <string name="rc_insight_rough_title">Rough Patch</string>
    <string name="rc_insight_rough_msg">Your recent flights have been a bit bumpier than you hoped. Remember that turbulence is uncomfortable but never dangerous.</string>

    <string name="rc_avg_overestimate">On average, you overestimated by %.1f points.</string>
    <string name="rc_avg_underestimate">On average, you underestimated by %.1f points.</string>
    <string name="rc_avg_accurate">On average, your predictions are perfectly accurate.</string>
    <string name="rc_catastrophe_gap_desc">(This is your \'Catastrophe Gap\' - the difference between fear and reality)</string>
    <string name="rc_reality_gap_desc">(Difference between expectation and reality)</string>

    <!-- Learn Sections -->
    <string name="learn_section_takeoff">Takeoff &amp; Climbing</string>
    <string name="learn_section_landing">Landing</string>

    <!-- Takeoff Questions -->
    <string name="takeoff_q1">Why does the whole plane vibrate and rattle before it even moves?</string>
    <string name="takeoff_a1">You\'re sitting there, the engines are still quiet, and suddenly the entire cabin starts shaking, rattling, and buzzing like something is loose or broken. It feels wrong and scary.\n\nHere\'s exactly what\'s happening:\n\nWhile you\'re waiting at the gate or taxiing, the pilots and the ground crew are doing last-second checks. The biggest shake usually comes when the pilots turn on the hydraulic pumps at full power and test the flight controls (ailerons, elevators, rudder).\n\nThose big control surfaces on the wings and tail move quickly left-right and up-down. When they do, the hydraulic lines and actuators make the whole airframe vibrate and transmit the movement into the cabin. It\'s the same as when you test the steering wheel of a car hard left and right - the whole car shudders a little.\n\nYou might also hear a loud whining or barking sound under the floor. That\'s the PTU (Power Transfer Unit), a normal hydraulic system that makes a loud \"dog barking\" noise on many Airbus planes (and similar noises on Boeings). It only runs when one hydraulic system is at lower pressure - completely routine.\n\nSometimes the air-conditioning packs are switched from ground power to the engines or APU, and that makes the floor vibrate for a few seconds.\n\nAll of this happens before the plane even starts rolling and it is 100% normal. Pilots do it on every single flight. The plane is not falling apart - it\'s just waking up its muscles and making sure everything moves freely before the takeoff run. Nothing is loose, nothing is broken. It\'s the aviation version of stretching before a sprint.\n\nOnce the engines spool up and you start moving, most of that pre-flight rattling disappears.\n\nYou\'re perfectly safe - the plane is just saying \"systems checked and ready.\"</string>

    <string name="takeoff_q2">What are all those clicking and clunking noises right before we start rolling?</string>
    <string name="takeoff_a2">Those sounds are the flight control surfaces (ailerons, rudder, elevators) being tested, hydraulic systems pressurizing, and the parking brake releasing. Pilots run through a checklist that involves moving various parts - each click and clunk is a system confirming it\'s ready for flight.</string>

    <string name="takeoff_q3">That drop or dip right after takeoff - are we falling back down?</string>
    <string name="takeoff_a3">No, you\'re not falling. It feels exactly like the plane just lost all lift and is dropping, but it\'s actually a normal (and deliberate) maneuver that happens on almost every single takeoff.\n\nHere\'s precisely what\'s going on:\n\nAs soon as the wheels leave the ground, the pilot pulls the nose up to a steep climb angle (usually 15-20 degrees). That gives you the strong \"pushing you back in your seat\" feeling.\n\nA few seconds later, at around 35-100 feet above the runway, the pilot reduces engine power from full takeoff thrust to a lower \"climb thrust.\" This is required by law and airline rules to save the engines and reduce noise over the airport area. The sudden drop in engine roar makes it feel like the power just disappeared.\n\nAt almost the same moment, the pilot lowers the nose slightly (from 18 degrees to about 10-12 degrees) so the plane accelerates to a safe climbing speed. That small pitch-down movement creates the unmistakable \"elevator drop\" or \"sinking\" sensation in your stomach.\n\nOn top of that, the huge flaps that were hanging down for takeoff start retracting. When the first stage of flaps comes up, the wing temporarily loses a tiny bit of lift, which adds to the sinking feeling.\n\nAll of this happens in the space of 5-10 seconds, usually below 500 feet. It feels dramatic because you\'re very low and your body isn\'t used to it, but the plane is climbing the entire time (often at 2,000-3,000 feet per minute). The altimeter is going up, not down.\n\nPilots do this on every flight, every day, millions of times a year. It\'s not an emergency, it\'s not a mistake, and the plane is nowhere near stalling or falling.\n\nIt\'s just the normal \"clean-up\" phase after takeoff: reduce power -> lower the nose a little -> retract flaps -> settle into a steady climb.\n\nNext time you feel that dip, remind yourself: \"That\'s just the pilot shifting gears.\"\n\nIt always passes in seconds, and then the ride smooths out. You\'re climbing safely the whole time.</string>

    <string name="takeoff_q4">Why do the engines suddenly get quieter the moment we\'re in the air? Did they turn off?</string>
    <string name="takeoff_a4">The engines are still running at high power. What changed is the noise abatement procedure: pilots reduce thrust slightly after clearing obstacles to minimize noise over residential areas. The plane is still climbing safely. You\'ll hear power increase again once past noise-sensitive zones.</string>

    <string name="takeoff_q5">The plane is still wobbling and rocking side to side - shouldn\'t it feel stable immediately?</string>
    <string name="takeoff_a5">No, it\'s completely normal for the plane to wobble, rock, and sway for the first 1-3 minutes after takeoff - even on a clear day. It does not mean the pilots have lost control or that something is wrong.\n\nHere\'s exactly why it happens:\n\nYou\'re flying through the air that was just above the ground.\n\nThe first 500-2,000 feet are full of uneven heat rising off the runway, buildings, and parking lots. That warm air acts like invisible speed bumps - it makes the plane bobble and rock exactly the way a boat rocks on choppy water near the shore. Once you climb above that layer (usually within a minute or two), it smooths out dramatically.\n\nThe pilots are \"cleaning up\" the plane.\n\nIn the first minute they are retracting flaps and slats in stages. Every time a big flap moves up, the wing shape changes a little, and the plane gives a small roll or wiggle until the autopilot or pilot trims it out. It\'s like shifting gears in a car - there\'s a tiny lurch each time.\n\nLow-level wind is almost always uneven.\n\nClose to the ground the wind speed and direction change every few seconds (wind shear or gusts). At cruising altitude the wind is usually steady, but down low the plane gets pushed left-right a bit until it climbs into smoother air.\n\nThe autopilot usually isn\'t fully engaged yet.\n\nOn many flights the pilots hand-fly the first few hundred feet, or the autopilot is only in a basic mode. They let the plane rock a little while they finish checklists and set the proper climb mode. Once everything is set (often below 5,000 feet), it locks in and feels rock-solid.\n\nEvery professional pilot expects this low-altitude wobble - they call it the \"departure bounce\" or \"low-level junk.\"\n\nIf the plane went from runway to glass-smooth the instant the wheels left the ground, that would actually be unusual.\n\nYou\'ll feel it settle very soon - usually before the seat-belt sign goes off.\n\nThe rocking is proof you\'re climbing through the messy air near the airport, not proof that anything is wrong. Once you\'re above a couple thousand feet, you\'ll be in the calm layer and it will feel like a different aircraft. Just hang on for another minute or two - the smooth part is coming.</string>

    <string name="takeoff_q6">What if the engine fails during the takeoff?</string>
    <string name="takeoff_a6">This is the big one that keeps most nervous flyers awake at night. Here\'s the straight truth:\n\nIt almost never happens.\n\nModern jet engines are designed to run for 50,000-100,000 hours between major overhauls. The chance of one quitting exactly during takeoff is roughly 1 in 2-3 million flights. You are literally more likely to be struck by lightning twice in the same year.\n\nEven if it does happen, the plane is built for it.\n\nEvery commercial jet is certified to take off, climb safely, and return to land with only one engine (or even with all engines failed on some aircraft after a certain speed). That rule is non-negotiable; the plane would never be allowed to fly passengers if it couldn\'t do it.\n\nThere are two very clear phases:\n\nBefore V1 (the \"decision speed\" you hear pilots talk about):\n\nIf an engine fails here, the pilots simply abort the takeoff. They brake hard, stay on the runway, and stop with plenty of pavement left. That\'s why runways are extra long. This happens a few times a year worldwide and almost nobody ever gets hurt.\n\nAfter V1 (usually 20-40 seconds before the wheels leave the ground):\n\nThe plane is already going fast enough that stopping is no longer the safest option. The pilots keep going, lift off normally, climb away on the remaining engine(s), circle back, and land in 10-20 minutes - usually without even declaring an emergency. Passengers often don\'t notice anything except a slightly louder engine noise and a turn back to the airport.\n\nReal-life examples:\n\nQantas 32 (A380, 2010) - massive engine explosion right after takeoff from Singapore. They flew for almost two hours on the remaining three engines and landed safely.\n\nBritish Airways 2276 (Boeing 777, Las Vegas 2015) - left engine caught fire during takeoff roll. Crew rejected takeoff, everyone walked away in under 90 seconds.\n\nHundreds of similar events every decade - zero fatalities in modern jets when crews follow the rules (which they always do).\n\nThe pilots train for this exact scenario every six months in the simulator - sometimes twice a year. They practice engine failure at the worst possible moment dozens of times so it becomes routine.\n\nBottom line: an engine failure on takeoff is spectacularly unlikely, and even if it happens the plane and crew are 100% prepared.\n\nYou are safer than you have ever been in a car on the highway.\n\nIf you ever hear the engines go uneven or see the plane turning back shortly after takeoff, remind yourself: \"This is the thing they train for every six months - it\'s handled.\"\n\nThen sit back. You\'ll be on the ground drinking coffee in 15 minutes.</string>

    <string name="takeoff_q7">The runway is wet or snowy - is it safe to takeoff?</string>
    <string name="takeoff_a7">Yes, it is safe. Airlines and airports have strict rules, and they don\'t guess.\n\nHere\'s exactly how it works:\n\nThere are three official runway conditions:\nDry -> normal performance\nWet -> slightly longer stopping distance, but still perfectly safe\nContaminated (standing water, slush, ice, compacted snow) -> special numbers\n\nIf the runway is just wet (rain, light water on the surface), pilots use \"wet performance\" tables. They already add hundreds or thousands of extra feet to the required runway length. On a normal day they might need 6,000 ft; on a wet day they calculate for 7,500-8,000 ft. If the runway is shorter than that, they simply wait or reduce weight (take less fuel or passengers - which happens automatically).\n\nIf there is slush, ice or heavy snow:\n\nThe airport measures the depth and type every 30-60 minutes and sends an official report (called SNOWTAM or runway condition report).\n\nPilots get the latest numbers on their iPads seconds before pushback. The plane\'s computer then recalculates exactly how much runway is needed.\n\nIf it\'s too slippery or too short -> the flight does not depart. No discussion. Hundreds of flights get delayed or cancelled every winter for exactly this reason. They would rather delay you six hours than take even a tiny risk.\n\nExtra safety margins built in:\n\nEven the \"wet\" or \"contaminated\" calculations include a 15% safety buffer required by law. That means the plane will stop or get airborne with hundreds of metres to spare, even if everything is worse than measured.\n\nBraking systems and tyres:\n\nModern aircraft tyres have water-channel grooves (like car tyres), and the anti-skid brakes work even better on a wet surface than on dry (they pulse 20-30 times a second to prevent skidding).\n\nReverse thrust and spoilers work the same in rain or snow.\n\nReal-world proof: in Europe and North America, thousands of planes take off and land every day in rain, snow, and slush. Serious incidents caused purely by a wet or snowy runway are very rare in the last 30 years.\n\nBottom line: if your plane is cleared to take off in the rain or snow, it means the numbers have been checked three times (airport, pilots, aircraft computer) and there is a huge safety margin.\n\nIf it wasn\'t safe, you would still be sitting at the gate.\n\nThe pilots want to get home to their families just as much as you do.</string>

    <string name="takeoff_q8">What if we get hit by a bird during takeoff?</string>
    <string name="takeoff_a8">Bird strikes happen - about 40 times a day worldwide - but the nightmare scenario you\'re picturing (both engines exploding, plane crashing) is practically science fiction.\n\nHere\'s exactly what happens in real life:\n\nEngines are literally tested by firing dead chickens at them:\n\nBefore any jet engine is certified, the manufacturer has to shoot frozen 4-8 lb birds straight into a running engine at full takeoff power (using a chicken cannon). The engine must keep running or shut down safely without fire or uncontained blades flying out. They do this dozens of times. Your engines have already survived worse than any real bird you\'ll meet.\n\n99.9% of bird strikes do almost nothing:\nSmall birds -> get shredded, you might hear a thud or smell burnt chicken for a minute.\nBig birds (geese, gulls) -> louder bang, possible vibration, maybe a few damaged fan blades.\n\nThe engine almost always keeps producing at least 70-90% power.\n\nDual-engine failures from bird strikes are one-in-millions rarities:\n\nThe famous \"Miracle on the Hudson\" (US Airways 1549, 2009) was a stunning exception: they hit a whole flock of Canada geese at exactly the wrong altitude (2,800 ft) and lost both engines completely, but glided to a safe ditching with zero fatalities. Tragically, a second such event occurred on December 29, 2024, with Jeju Air Flight 2216 in South Korea - a Boeing 737-800 that ingested a flock of large migratory ducks (Baikal teals) into both engines during approach, leading to dual failure, a belly landing, runway excursion, and 179 fatalities out of 181 aboard. These are the only two confirmed cases in commercial jet history of simultaneous multiple large bird ingestion causing total dual-engine flameout. Every other dual-engine failure on record has been from volcanic ash, fuel issues, or other non-bird causes.\n\nIf one engine is badly damaged during takeoff:\n\nThe plane climbs away on the remaining engine (they are certified to do this even on the hottest day with full passengers). The pilots shut the damaged engine down, fly a big circuit, and land 10-20 minutes later. Passengers usually don\'t even realise how serious it was until they read the news the next day.\n\nAirports actively chase birds away:\nAir-horns, pyrotechnics, falcons, dogs, radar systems, grass management - they spend millions doing it.\nTakeoffs and landings are timed to avoid peak bird activity when possible.\nIf a big flock is near the runway, they delay the departure until it\'s clear.\n\nBottom line: if you hear a loud bang or see feathers on takeoff, remind yourself:\n\n\"Engines eat birds for breakfast. This plane was literally designed and tested for this exact moment.\"\n\nYou\'ll be on the ground again in 15 minutes, drinking coffee and reading the headline about how routine it was.</string>

    <string name="learn_section_flight">During the Flight</string>

    <string name="flight_q1">What if we run out of fuel over the ocean?</string>
    <string name="flight_a1">It\'s not going to happen. And even in the handful of times it has happened in aviation history, every single passenger walked away safely.\n\nHere\'s why running out of fuel isn\'t the disaster you\'re imagining:\n\n<b>You\'re Carrying a Ridiculous Amount of Extra Fuel</b>\n\nEvery flight is legally required to carry:\n• Fuel to reach your destination\n• Fuel to fly to an alternate airport (often 1,000+ miles away)\n• An additional 45 minutes of flying time after that\n• Whatever extra the captain decides to add for weather or delays\n\nIn practice, a typical transatlantic flight takes off with <b>3-5 hours of extra fuel</b> beyond what\'s needed. You could fly to your destination, completely miss it, divert to another continent, and still circle for nearly an hour. That\'s why planes land with 8-20 tons still in the tanks—enough to fly back halfway across the ocean.\n\n<b>The Fuel Is Monitored Every Single Second</b>\n\nFuel isn\'t guessed or estimated—it\'s measured precisely:\n• Ground crews load it and document the exact amount\n• Pilots cross-check the numbers on paper and on multiple cockpit screens\n• Aircraft computers monitor burn rate in real time, second by second\n\nIf the plane is burning even slightly more fuel than expected (strong headwinds, weather detours), alarms sound in the cockpit and the pilots divert to a closer airport while they still have <b>hours of fuel remaining</b>. They don\'t wait until it\'s close—they act early, when there\'s still a massive cushion.\n\n<b>Ocean Routes Are Surrounded by Emergency Airports</b>\n\nThat vast empty ocean isn\'t actually empty. Under international ETOPS/EDTO rules, every single point on your route is within <b>180-370 minutes of a suitable airport</b>—even flying on one engine.\n\nThat\'s why transatlantic routes pass near:\n• Iceland (Keflavik)\n• Greenland (Narsarsuaq, Kangerlussuaq)\n• The Azores (Lajes)\n• Newfoundland (Gander, Goose Bay)\n• Ireland (Shannon)\n\nThese aren\'t just tiny airstrips—they\'re fully equipped airports with long runways, emergency services, and fuel. Diversions happen several times a week worldwide for medical issues, weather, or technical reasons. Routine.\n\n<b>The Only Real-World Cases? Everyone Survived</b>\n\nSince commercial jets began flying passengers in the 1950s, fuel exhaustion has happened fewer than a dozen times on scheduled flights. <b>Not one ended in fatalities from the fuel issue itself.</b> Here are the most famous:\n\n<b>Gimli Glider (Air Canada 143, 1983):</b> A unit conversion error (metric vs. imperial) meant the plane took off with half the fuel it needed. Both engines quit at 41,000 feet over Canada. The pilots glided 65 miles and landed at an abandoned airstrip. Rough landing, a few minor injuries during evacuation, but all 69 people walked away. The result? Mandatory fuel calculation cross-checks and better crew training became global standards.\n\n<b>Air Transat 236 (2001):</b> A fuel leak over the Atlantic drained the tanks completely. The crew glided 75 miles—the longest glide in commercial jet history—and landed at Lajes Air Base in the Azores. All 306 passengers and crew survived without serious injury. The result? Stricter post-maintenance inspections and enhanced fuel monitoring systems worldwide.\n\nThese weren\'t lucky accidents—they were <b>successful emergency procedures</b> built on training, redundancy, and the fact that modern jets glide exceptionally well. Every incident led to system-wide improvements that make repeats nearly impossible.\n\n<b>Modern Jets Can Glide for Miles</b>\n\nIf both engines somehow lost power, you wouldn\'t drop from the sky. From cruising altitude (35,000-40,000 feet), a typical twin-engine jet can glide for <b>100-150+ miles</b>—that\'s 20-30 minutes of controlled flight. Widebody aircraft like the 777 or A350 can glide even farther.\n\nDuring that time:\n• Flight controls still work (powered by backup systems)\n• The autopilot can still fly the plane\n• A ram air turbine automatically deploys to generate emergency power\n• Pilots have plenty of time to find a suitable landing spot\n\nIt\'s not a freefall—it\'s a controlled descent with options.\n\n<b>Bottom Line</b>\n\nYou\'re carrying more spare fuel than most cars have in their entire tank. The plane monitors every drop. Emergency airports line every ocean route. And in the extraordinary event fuel ever ran low, you\'d glide safely to a landing.\n\nRunning out of fuel isn\'t a realistic fear—it\'s a solved problem backed by decades of engineering, regulation, and real-world proof.\n\nBreathe easy. The system has your back.</string>

    <string name="flight_q2">Why does the plane keep suddenly dropping or jumping 50-100 ft? (Clear-air turbulence)</string>
    <string name="flight_a2">That stomach-lurching drop feels like you just fell hundreds of feet, but you didn\'t. The plane dropped maybe 10-30 metres at most—and it was never in danger.\n\nHere\'s what\'s really happening and why it\'s completely safe:\n\n<b>It\'s Called Clear-Air Turbulence (CAT)</b>\n\nAt cruising altitude, powerful jet stream winds create invisible \"waves\" and shear zones in the air. When the plane crosses from one air mass to another, the wind speed or direction can change by 20-50 knots in seconds.\n\nYour body feels that transition like hitting a speed bump at 500 mph—sharp and jarring—but to the plane, it\'s just a ripple. There\'s no actual \"air pocket\" or \"hole in the sky.\" The air is still there; it just shifted.\n\n<b>The Plane Is Built for This</b>\n\nCommercial jets are certified to withstand <b>vertical gusts up to +50 ft/sec</b> (that\'s over 3,000 feet per minute) without any structural damage. That\'s like driving over a cliff and the car not even noticing.\n\nA typical turbulence bump? Only 10-20 ft/sec—well inside the safety margin. The wings are designed to flex and absorb the force, which is why you see them bounce and bend. That flexing is the safety system working perfectly.\n\n<b>Your Body Exaggerates the Drop</b>\n\nWhen you feel that sickening lurch, your brain screams \"We just fell 500 feet!\" In reality, the plane might have dropped 50-150 feet over 2-4 seconds, then climbed right back.\n\nThe altimeter barely moves. Your inner ear and stomach amplify the sensation because there\'s no visual reference at 35,000 feet—just clouds or darkness. If you could see the horizon, it would look like a tiny wobble.\n\n<b>Pilots Usually See It Coming</b>\n\nMost of the time, turbulence isn\'t a surprise:\n• Weather satellites track jet streams and unstable air masses\n• Planes ahead report rough patches (PIREPs) that go out to every flight\n• Radar can detect some types of turbulence minutes in advance\n\nThat\'s why the seatbelt sign suddenly comes on when the sky looks perfectly clear. The pilots just got a warning and are giving you time to buckle up.\n\nWhen CAT is truly unexpected, they immediately slow to <b>turbulence penetration speed</b> (usually 270-280 knots), which smooths out the bumps and reduces stress on the airframe.\n\n<b>Not a Single Crash in Over 60 Years</b>\n\nSince the 1960s, <b>not one modern commercial passenger jet has ever broken up or crashed because of clear-air turbulence.</b> Not one.\n\nThe worst recorded cases caused injuries to unbuckled passengers or crew, but the aircraft stayed intact and landed safely. Modern wing design, materials, and forecasting have made structural failure from CAT essentially impossible.\n\n<b>What to Remember</b>\n\nNext time you feel that sudden drop, tell yourself:\n\n<b>\"It\'s the air version of a pothole. The plane just shrugged it off, and we\'re already back to smooth air.\"</b>\n\nTurbulence always passes—usually in seconds, sometimes in a minute or two. Keep your seatbelt loosely fastened, and you\'re as safe as you\'d be sitting in your living room.</string>

    <string name="flight_q3">The engines just got quieter - did they reduce power too much or turn one off?</string>
    <string name="flight_a3">No, they didn\'t turn anything off and they didn\'t cut power too much. The sudden drop in engine noise is <b>100% normal and deliberate.</b>\n\nHere\'s exactly what you just heard:\n\n<b>Cruise-Climb or Step-Climb Power Reduction</b>\n\nRight after levelling off or after a step-climb to a higher altitude, the autopilot switches from \"take-off/climb thrust\" (loud) to \"cruise thrust\" (much quieter). It happens automatically and can cut the engine noise by <b>30-50% in a few seconds.</b> It feels dramatic because the cabin was already quiet after takeoff.\n\n<b>Cost-Index / Economy Cruise Setting</b>\n\nAirlines programme the plane to fly at the most fuel-efficient power setting once at cruising altitude. That means the engines idle back to around <b>85-92% N1</b> (fan speed) instead of the 100-105% they used for climb.\n\nPerfectly safe—the engines are designed to run like this for <b>12+ hours.</b>\n\n<b>You\'re Now in Thinner Air at 35,000-39,000 ft</b>\n\nThe higher you go, the less air there is for the engines to \"scream\" against. Same thrust, way less noise inside the cabin. Physics, not problems.\n\n<b>If One Engine Actually Was Shut Down (Extremely Rare)</b>\n\nYou would hear:\n• A loud yaw (the plane slews sideways)\n• The cabin lights would flicker\n• Pilots would announce it within seconds\n\nA quiet engine change without any of that = <b>normal cruise mode.</b>\n\n<b>Real-World Proof</b>\n\nEvery long-haul flight you\'ve ever been on did this exact thing 10-30 minutes after takeoff.\n\nThe engines are now purring efficiently instead of roaring—exactly what they\'re supposed to do for the next 8-12 hours. <b>Nothing is wrong. In fact, everything is going exactly right.</b>\n\nEnjoy the quiet—it means you\'re safely in cruise.</string>

    <string name="flight_q4">What if both engines fail at the same time up here?</string>
    <string name="flight_a4">This is the nightmare scenario everyone imagines, but here\'s the truth: it almost never happens, and when it does, planes don\'t just drop from the sky.\n\n<b>Planes Are Excellent Gliders</b>\n\nFrom 35,000 feet (typical cruising altitude), a modern jet can glide for <b>100-150 miles</b>—that\'s about 20-30 minutes of controlled flight with no engines at all.\n\n• A Boeing 737 has a glide ratio of about 17:1 (travels 17 feet forward for every 1 foot of descent)\n• An Airbus A320 is similar at 16:1\n• Larger aircraft like the 777 or A350 can glide even farther\n\nThat gives pilots plenty of time to find an airport, troubleshoot, and plan a landing.\n\n<b>Why Dual Engine Failure Is Extraordinarily Rare</b>\n\nEngines are built completely separately—different oil systems, different fuel feeds, different computers. For both to fail simultaneously, something external has to affect them:\n\n• Fuel exhaustion (only happens with human error, and modern systems have multiple warnings)\n• Volcanic ash (pilots receive warnings and avoid ash clouds)\n• Bird strike to both engines (extremely rare at cruise altitude; birds don\'t fly that high)\n• Severe icing (only at low altitude, and anti-ice systems prevent this)\n\nIn the entire history of commercial jet aviation (70+ years), dual engine failure at cruise altitude has happened fewer than 10 times—out of hundreds of millions of flights.\n\n<b>Real-World Examples—Everyone Survived</b>\n\n<b>Air Transat 236 (2001):</b> Fuel leak over the Atlantic. Both engines stopped at 39,000 feet. The crew glided <b>75 miles</b> to an airbase in the Azores. All 306 people walked away safely. It\'s still the longest glide in commercial aviation history.\n\n<b>British Airways 9 (1982):</b> Flew through volcanic ash, all four engines failed. The crew descended, the engines cooled and restarted, and they landed safely in Jakarta. All 263 people survived.\n\n<b>US Airways 1549 (2009):</b> Bird strike knocked out both engines at just 2,800 feet after takeoff. Captain Sully ditched in the Hudson River. All 155 people survived—and this was at low altitude with almost no time to react.\n\n<b>What Happens If Engines Quit</b>\n\n1. The plane becomes a glider, descending gently at about 1,500-2,000 feet per minute\n2. Flight controls still work—a <b>Ram Air Turbine (RAT)</b> automatically deploys from the belly, using wind to generate backup power\n3. Pilots follow the engine restart checklist (often engines can be restarted)\n4. If restart fails, they find the nearest suitable airport and glide there\n5. Emergency services are alerted and the runway is cleared\n\n<b>Pilots Train for This Every Six Months</b>\n\nIn simulator training, every pilot practices dual engine failure multiple times per year. They know exactly what to do, how far they can glide, and where the nearest airports are.\n\nIt\'s not a panic situation—it\'s a checklist situation.\n\n<b>The Bottom Line</b>\n\nDual engine failure at cruise altitude is vanishingly rare. When it has happened, crews have had time, options, and training to bring everyone down safely.\n\nYour plane isn\'t held up by hope—it\'s held up by physics. Even without engines, those wings keep working.\n\nYou\'re safe.</string>

    <string name="flight_q5">We\'re flying over the ocean/mountains with no airport for hours - what if something goes wrong?</string>
    <string name="flight_a5">That empty expanse below feels terrifying, but you\'re actually surrounded by more runways than you think, and the plane is built exactly for this scenario.\n\nHere\'s the real picture:\n\nYou\'re never truly \"nowhere\"\n\nOn every long over-water or remote route, the flight plan is drawn so that at any moment—even on one engine—you are within 180-370 minutes of a suitable airport (ETOPS/EDTO rules). That means places like:\nIceland, Greenland, the Azores, Canary Islands\nGoose Bay, Gander, Iqaluit (Canada)\nShemya, Anchorage (Alaska)\nHawaii, Fiji, Tahiti in the Pacific\n\nThese are pre-approved emergency airfields with long runways, fire trucks, and medical teams on standby 24/7.\n\nThe plane is certified to fly hours on one engine\n\nYour aircraft (737, A320, 777, A350, etc.) has been tested and proven to fly, climb, and cruise for 3-6+ hours with one engine completely shut down. Losing one engine doesn\'t mean you\'re falling—it just means a slower cruise and a diversion to one of those fields.\n\nIf both engines quit (the absolute nightmare)\n\nYou still glide 100-180 miles from cruising altitude (20-30 minutes). That\'s enough to reach land or a ship in almost every case. Real examples (Air Transat 236, US Airways 1549) both reached safe landing spots from the middle of nowhere.\n\nConstant tracking and instant help\n\nADS-B and satellite coverage mean ATC and the airline know your exact position every second.\n\nIf anything goes wrong, military jets can be scrambled, ships redirected, and the closest runway cleared in minutes.\n\nMany remote airfields (e.g., Lajes in the Azores, Keflavik in Iceland) exist mainly for transatlantic emergencies—they get a few diversions every year and handle them perfectly.\n\nReal-life proof\n\nEvery year a handful of flights divert to these \"middle-of-nowhere\" bases for medical issues, technical problems, or weather. Passengers get off, have coffee, and continue the next day. Zero drama.\n\nSo when you look out and see nothing but water or mountains, remember: the route was drawn around invisible safety islands, and the plane can reach one of them even in the worst case.\n\nYou\'re not flying over emptiness—you\'re flying a carefully planned highway in the sky with emergency exits every 1,000 miles.</string>

    <string name="flight_q6">What if the cabin suddenly depressurises? (oxygen masks drop)</string>
    <string name="flight_a6">This looks terrifying in movies, but here\'s the reality: it almost never happens, and when it does, the systems work exactly as designed.\n\n<b>What Depressurization Actually Means</b>\n\nThe cabin is pressurized to feel like you\'re at about 6,000-8,000 feet (like Denver). If pressure drops to unsafe levels, oxygen masks automatically drop from the ceiling. The system detects the problem and deploys the solution instantly.\n\n<b>The Masks Drop Automatically—You Have Plenty of Time</b>\n\nThe moment cabin altitude exceeds safe limits:\n• Yellow masks drop instantly from the ceiling\n• You don\'t need to do anything to trigger them\n• Each mask provides <b>12-15 minutes of continuous oxygen</b>\n• That\'s more than enough, because...\n\n<b>The Pilots Are Already Descending—Fast</b>\n\nThe second depressurization is detected (alarms go off in the cockpit), the pilots do this:\n\n1. <b>Put on their own oxygen masks</b> (takes 2 seconds)\n2. <b>Disconnect autopilot and start an emergency descent</b>\n3. <b>Point the nose down steeply</b> (you\'ll feel like you\'re diving)\n4. <b>Descend at 3,000-4,000 feet per minute</b> (very fast)\n\nFrom 40,000 feet to 10,000 feet (where you can breathe normally) takes only <b>7-10 minutes.</b>\n\nYour mask has 12-15 minutes of oxygen. You\'ll be breathing normal air again long before it runs out.\n\n<b>What You\'ll Experience</b>\n\n• A whooshing sound\n• Your ears will pop (like a fast elevator)\n• The cabin might get cold\n• Brief fog or mist (just condensation)\n• The plane will pitch down and descend quickly—<b>this is correct and deliberate</b>\n• Masks drop from above\n• Pilots may announce "Put on your oxygen masks" or focus silently on flying\n\n<b>What You Should Do</b>\n\n1. <b>Pull the mask toward you firmly</b> (this starts the oxygen flow)\n2. <b>Place it over your nose and mouth</b>\n3. <b>Breathe normally</b>—the oxygen is flowing even if the bag doesn\'t inflate much\n4. <b>Secure your own mask first, then help others</b> (you can\'t help anyone if you pass out)\n5. <b>Stay seated with your seatbelt on</b>\n\nThat\'s it. The pilots handle everything else.\n\n<b>The Plane Stays Flyable</b>\n\nLosing cabin pressure doesn\'t mean the plane is failing. The structure stays intact, the wings keep working, the engines keep running, and flight controls keep responding.\n\nThe plane simply can\'t stay at high altitude anymore—so it descends to where the air is thick enough to breathe naturally, then continues to the nearest airport.\n\n<b>How Rare Is This?</b>\n\nSignificant depressurization events happen roughly once in every several million flights. Modern aircraft are thoroughly tested, and when masks do deploy, pilots follow well-practiced procedures that lead to safe landings.\n\n<b>The Bottom Line</b>\n\nIf those yellow masks ever drop in front of you:\n• Pull one down firmly\n• Put it on and breathe\n• Stay calm—the pilots are already diving to safe altitude\n• You\'ll be breathing normal air again in less than 10 minutes\n\nIt\'s a solved problem with clear procedures, reliable equipment, and well-trained crews. You\'re going to be fine.</string>

    <string name="flight_q7">What if there is a fire on board?</string>
    <string name="flight_a7">Aircraft are designed with multiple layers of fire prevention and suppression systems. Fire safety is one of the most stringently regulated aspects of aviation.\n\n<b>Detection Happens Instantly</b>\n\nSmoke and heat detectors are installed throughout the aircraft:\n• Every cargo hold\n• All lavatories\n• Engine compartments\n• Avionics bays\n• Cabin ceiling areas\n\nThe moment any sensor detects smoke or heat, alarms sound in the cockpit immediately—often within seconds.\n\n<b>Suppression Is Automatic and Built-In</b>\n\n<b>Cargo holds:</b> Pilots press a button and fire suppression bottles automatically flood the hold with extinguishing agent (usually Halon or equivalent). This starves any fire of oxygen and keeps it contained for the entire flight.\n\n<b>Engines:</b> If an engine overheats or catches fire, dedicated fire bottles discharge automatically or at the push of a button. The affected engine can be shut down, and the plane continues flying safely on the remaining engine(s).\n\n<b>Cabin:</b> Flight attendants carry multiple large fire extinguishers and are extensively trained to use them. They practice fire scenarios regularly.\n\n<b>Everything Is Fire-Resistant</b>\n\nBy law, every material inside the aircraft must meet strict fire safety standards:\n• Seat cushions and fabrics are fire-resistant\n• Wall panels and ceiling materials won\'t support flame spread\n• Carpets and insulation are specially treated\n• Even the cargo liners are fire-proof\n\nThese materials are tested to withstand direct flame exposure without spreading fire, buying precious time for suppression systems and crew to act.\n\n<b>The Rule: Land Immediately</b>\n\nIf fire or smoke is confirmed, pilots follow one simple rule: <b>get on the ground as soon as possible.</b>\n\n• They declare an emergency\n• Air traffic control clears the way\n• The nearest suitable airport is chosen\n• Emergency services are alerted and ready on the runway\n\nTypically, you\'ll be on the ground within 15-30 minutes of the first indication.\n\n<b>Crew Training Is Extensive</b>\n\nFlight attendants train for fire scenarios <b>every single year</b> in their recurrent training:\n• How to locate the source\n• How to use extinguishers effectively\n• How to coordinate with the cockpit\n• How to manage an emergency evacuation if needed\n\nPilots also practice fire emergencies in the simulator every six months—engine fires, cargo fires, electrical fires—all of them.\n\n<b>How Rare Is This?</b>\n\nSignificant onboard fires are extraordinarily rare in modern aviation. Most "fire" events turn out to be:\n• Burnt food in the galley oven (handled in seconds)\n• Overheated electronic device (isolated immediately)\n• Smoke from a mechanical issue (not an actual fire)\n\nThe systems, materials, and crew are so effective that actual uncontrolled fires almost never occur.\n\n<b>The Bottom Line</b>\n\nIf there\'s ever smoke or fire on your flight:\n• The crew will detect it immediately\n• Suppression systems will activate\n• The plane will divert to the nearest airport\n• You\'ll be on the ground quickly and safely\n\nFire safety isn\'t an afterthought—it\'s engineered into every surface, every system, and every crew member\'s training. You\'re protected by multiple redundant layers designed specifically to prevent and contain any fire before it becomes dangerous.</string>

    <string name="flight_q8">What if ice builds up on the wings and we can\'t get it off?</string>
    <string name="flight_a8">Ice on wings is a real concern, which is why aircraft have multiple systems specifically designed to prevent and remove it.\n\n<b>Anti-Icing Works Continuously</b>\n\nDuring flight in cold, moist conditions:\n• Hot air from the engines (bleed air) is automatically routed to the leading edges of the wings, tail, and engine inlets\n• This keeps critical surfaces warm enough that ice can\'t form in the first place\n• The system activates automatically when sensors detect icing conditions\n• It runs continuously for as long as needed—there\'s no "running out" of hot air\n\n<b>Before Takeoff: Nothing Leaves the Gate With Ice</b>\n\nIn winter weather, de-icing is mandatory:\n• Trucks spray heated fluid that melts all frost, snow, and ice\n• A second coating of anti-ice fluid prevents new ice from forming for 10-60 minutes (depending on conditions)\n• Pilots visually inspect or use tools to verify wings are completely clean\n• If ice reforms while waiting, the process is repeated\n\n<b>No plane is allowed to take off with ice on the wings. Ever.</b>\n\n<b>Pilots Monitor It Constantly</b>\n\n• Cockpit ice detectors trigger alerts if any buildup starts\n• Wing inspection lights let pilots check leading edges at night\n• If icing becomes a concern, pilots can descend to warmer air or change route\n• Weather forecasts and pilot reports help them avoid known icing areas\n\n<b>At High Speed, Ice Doesn\'t Stick Well</b>\n\nAt cruising speeds (450-550 mph), air friction generates heat and ice sheds naturally. The main concern is during climb and descent through clouds, which is exactly when the anti-ice systems are running.\n\n<b>The Bottom Line</b>\n\nIce prevention is a solved problem in modern aviation:\n• Automatic heating systems run whenever needed\n• Ground de-icing ensures clean wings before departure\n• Pilots can avoid or exit icing conditions if systems are overwhelmed (which is extremely rare)\n\nYou won\'t take off with ice, and you won\'t accumulate dangerous ice in flight. The systems are designed specifically to make sure of it.</string>

    <string name="flight_q9">What if we get hit by lightning?</string>
    <string name="flight_a9">Being struck by lightning sounds terrifying, but here\'s the truth: it happens regularly, and it\'s completely harmless.\n\n<b>Planes Are Designed to Be Hit</b>\n\nThe entire aircraft acts as a <b>Faraday cage</b>:\n• The aluminum skin or carbon composite with embedded metal mesh conducts electricity perfectly\n• Lightning enters at one point (usually the nose or wingtip)\n• It travels around the outside of the fuselage\n• It exits at another point (tail or opposite wingtip)\n• Passengers and systems inside are completely shielded\n\nYou\'re safer inside the plane than you would be in a building.\n\n<b>What You\'ll Experience</b>\n\n• A bright flash of light\n• A loud bang or crack (like a nearby gunshot)\n• Possibly a brief flicker of cabin lights\n\nThat\'s it. The plane doesn\'t shake, drop, or change course. Most passengers don\'t even realize it happened unless they were looking out the window.\n\n<b>All Critical Systems Are Protected</b>\n\n• Flight controls, engines, and avionics have triple redundancy\n• Surge protectors absorb any electrical spikes\n• Fuel tanks use inerting systems so sparks can\'t ignite fuel\n• Wiring and electronics are heavily shielded\n\n<b>After a Strike</b>\n\nPilots get a notification, report it to maintenance, and the plane lands normally. On the ground, engineers inspect for tiny burn marks (usually just surface scorch). In 99% of cases, the plane flies its next scheduled flight the same day.\n\n<b>How Common Is This?</b>\n\nThe average commercial aircraft is struck by lightning <b>1-2 times per year.</b> For the entire global fleet, that\'s multiple strikes happening every single day.\n\nIn over 50 years of modern commercial aviation, <b>zero passengers or crew have been injured</b> by a lightning strike, and <b>zero planes have crashed</b> because of one.\n\n<b>The Bottom Line</b>\n\nIf you see a flash and hear a loud bang during a flight:\n• The plane just did its job as a Faraday cage\n• All systems are still working perfectly\n• You\'ll continue to your destination as planned\n\nIt\'s startling, yes—but it\'s one of the most thoroughly tested and least dangerous things that can happen to an aircraft.</string>

    <string name="flight_q10">What If We Lose Electricity on a Plane?</string>
    <string name="flight_a10">Aircraft have multiple independent power sources, making total electrical failure virtually impossible. But even if every primary system failed, backups would keep the plane flying safely.\n\n<b>Multiple Power Sources</b>\n\nCommercial aircraft typically have <b>at least four</b> independent ways to generate electricity:\n\n1. <b>Engine-driven generators</b> - Each engine has its own generator producing power while it runs\n2. <b>Auxiliary Power Unit (APU)</b> - A small jet engine in the tail that can generate electricity independently of the main engines (can be started in flight)\n3. <b>Ram Air Turbine (RAT)</b> - A small turbine that automatically deploys into the airstream if all other power fails. Wind spins it, generating enough power for essential systems\n4. <b>Batteries</b> - Multiple batteries that can power critical systems temporarily\n\n<b>What the RAT Powers</b>\n\nIf all generators failed (extremely rare), the RAT provides enough electricity for:\n• Essential flight instruments\n• Flight controls (hydraulic pumps)\n• Basic communications\n• Navigation systems\n\nThat\'s everything pilots need to fly and land safely.\n\n<b>Planes Can Glide</b>\n\nEven without electrical power, aircraft are designed to glide efficiently:\n• From cruising altitude (35,000 ft), a commercial jet can glide 100-150 miles\n• That gives pilots 20-30 minutes to reach an airport\n• Flight controls work mechanically or via hydraulic pressure (which the RAT maintains)\n\n<b>How Rare Is This?</b>\n\nComplete electrical failure on a modern commercial aircraft is virtually unheard of. When electrical issues do occur, they\'re typically:\n• A single component failure (one generator)\n• Other systems immediately take over\n• Flights continue normally or divert out of caution\n\nThe redundancy is so extensive that losing one or even two power sources doesn\'t create an emergency.\n\n<b>Pilots Train for This</b>\n\nElectrical emergencies are part of simulator training every six months. Pilots practice flying with minimal systems, using backup instruments and procedures.\n\n<b>The Bottom Line</b>\n\nYou won\'t lose all electrical power, but if you somehow did:\n• The RAT deploys automatically\n• Essential systems stay powered\n• The plane continues flying and can land safely\n• Pilots know exactly what to do\n\nLayers upon layers of redundancy make electrical failure one of the least realistic concerns in modern aviation.</string>

    <!-- Landing Items -->
    <string name="landing_q1">How Pilots Decide If It\'s Safe to Land</string>
    <string name="landing_a1">If you\'ve ever looked out the window at rain-soaked runways or felt turbulence during approach and wondered \"Should we really be landing in this?\", here\'s what you need to know: pilots aren\'t making split-second guesses. They\'re following a systematic, multi-layered decision-making process that begins long before takeoff.\n\n<b>It Starts Hours Before Departure</b>\n\nBefore every flight, pilots meet 60 to 90 minutes beforehand to review weather conditions at departure, destination, and alternate airports. They examine forecasts, wind, visibility, precipitation, and potential hazards like thunderstorms or icing.\n\nThe airline calculates not just fuel for the journey, but extra fuel for holding patterns if needed and enough to divert to an alternate airport if landing becomes unsafe.\n\n<b>The Tools Pilots Use</b>\n\n<b>Weather Radar:</b> Onboard and ground-based systems show precipitation, thunderstorms, and turbulence along the route and at the destination.\n\n<b>Real-Time Airport Data:</b> Automated systems constantly measure wind speed, visibility, temperature, cloud ceiling, and runway conditions.\n\n<b>Pilot Reports:</b> Other pilots who\'ve recently landed share reports about actual conditions—turbulence levels, wind shear, braking effectiveness.\n\n<b>Air Traffic Control:</b> Controllers monitor weather patterns and relay information from multiple aircraft.\n\n<b>Key Decision Factors</b>\n\n<b>Wind Conditions</b>\n\nWhen calculating landing distance, 150% of any tail wind must be used, but only 50% of headwind may be used. This ensures a comfortable safety margin. Crosswinds have specific limits for each aircraft type—if exceeded, pilots wait or divert to a runway better aligned with the wind.\n\n<b>Visibility and Cloud Ceiling</b>\n\nModern instrument landing systems can guide aircraft to the runway even in fog, when pilots can\'t see it until the final moments. However, there are minimum visibility requirements based on the airport\'s equipment and aircraft capabilities. Below these minimums, landing isn\'t permitted.\n\n<b>Runway Conditions</b>\n\nA dry runway provides maximum friction. When runways are wet, snow-covered, or icy, pilots must calculate whether they have enough runway length to stop safely. Taking off and landing on contaminated runways requires complicated calculations of aircraft performance. If the calculations show insufficient stopping distance, the landing is not attempted.\n\n<b>Thunderstorms</b>\n\nThunderstorms are treated with extreme caution. Pilots are trained to be risk-averse and simply avoid bad weather. When thunderstorms are near the airport, pilots can hold and wait (a thunderstorm typically lasts 90 minutes), request a different approach path, or divert to another airport.\n\n<b>Multiple Layers of Safety</b>\n\n<b>The pilots</b> have authority to refuse any landing they deem unsafe, even if air traffic control clears them.\n\n<b>Air traffic control</b> monitors conditions and can recommend or require diversions.\n\n<b>Regulatory minimums</b> set clear thresholds below which landing is not permitted.\n\n<b>The go-around option:</b> Even during final approach, pilots can abort the landing, add power, and climb away to try again or divert. Go-arounds are routine procedures with no pressure to \"make it work.\"\n\n<b>What \"Bad Weather\" Really Means</b>\n\nCommercial airliners can fly in almost all weather conditions. Rain, even heavy rain, doesn\'t prevent landing—pilots adjust for wet runway braking. Strong winds might make for a bumpy approach, but modern aircraft handle significant crosswinds. Fog doesn\'t stop landing because instrument systems guide the aircraft precisely.\n\nThe conditions that actually prevent landing are rare: thunderstorms directly over the airport, winds exceeding aircraft limits, visibility below certified minimums, or runway contamination so severe that stopping calculations fail.\n\n<b>The Conservative Culture</b>\n\nAviation has a deeply conservative safety culture. Pilots are trained to be risk averse. Flying into adverse weather is something most would never purposely do.\n\nWhen you see rain on the runway or feel turbulence on approach, remember: your pilots have more information, better training, clearer guidelines, more experience, and both the authority and expectation to decline any landing they\'re not confident about.\n\nThe fact that they\'ve chosen to land means they\'ve systematically evaluated multiple factors and determined it\'s safe.\n\n<b>The Bottom Line</b>\n\nPilots don\'t land in conditions they\'re uncertain about. The decision is based on comprehensive weather data, aircraft performance calculations, regulatory requirements, and multiple oversight layers.\n\nWhen passengers see scary-looking weather, pilots see data, numbers, and procedures. They know the aircraft\'s capabilities, the runway\'s condition, and exactly what safety margins exist.\n\nYour anxiety is understandable—it looks dangerous. But pilots aren\'t sharing your uncertainty. They know, based on systematic evaluation, whether it\'s safe. And they have every incentive to get that decision right.\n\nThe next time you\'re approaching in bad weather and your anxiety spikes, remember: your pilots made the decision to land based on far more information than what you see out the window. They\'ve been trained for years to make exactly this decision, in exactly these conditions.\n\nTrust the process. It works.</string>

    <string name="landing_q2">Why the Wings Flex and Wobble on Landing</string>
    <string name="landing_a2" formatted="false">If you\'re sitting by the window and can see the wing, you\'ve probably noticed how much it moves. It bends upward in flight, then ripples and flexes the moment the wheels touch the runway. Those smooth, flowing motions are completely normal — and they\'re one of the smartest safety features on the plane.\n\nHere\'s why it happens and why it keeps you safer.\n\n<b>1. Wings are built to flex — on purpose</b>\n\nA Boeing 787\'s wingtips can move upward more than 8 metres (26 feet) in flight.\nAn Airbus A350 can flex nearly 9 metres at the tips.\nEvery modern jet is designed this way, whether the wings are aluminium or carbon fibre.\n\nEngineers make the wings flexible so they can absorb huge forces instead of fighting them. A stiff wing would transfer every bump and gust straight to the cabin. A flexible wing soaks up the energy like a shock absorber.\n\n<b>2. What\'s happening at touchdown</b>\n\nWhile you\'re descending, the wings are bent upward because they\'re producing lift. The moment the wheels touch:\n• Lift disappears in a split second.\n• All the aircraft\'s weight shifts to the landing gear.\n• The wings gently spring back toward their natural shape.\n\nThat smooth "unloading" is what creates the graceful ripple you see. Any leftover energy makes the wing oscillate a couple of times — just like a diving board settling after someone jumps off.\n\n<b>3. Windy landings make the movement even more noticeable</b>\n\nIn gusty or crosswind conditions the wings are constantly adjusting right until touchdown. When the plane finally settles on the runway, all that stored energy is released at once, so the flexing looks more dramatic. The more the wing moves, the more energy it just absorbed for you.\n\n<b>4. Real-world testing proves how strong they are</b>\n\nBefore any new aircraft flies passengers, the wings are tested to extremes:\n• The plane is bolted to the ground.\n• Hydraulic rams bend the wings far beyond anything they\'ll ever experience in service — usually 150% of the maximum load they\'ll ever see.\n• The wings have to hold that position for several seconds and then return perfectly to shape.\n\nThe 787\'s wings were flexed almost 8 metres upward in public testing — and sprang back as if nothing happened.\n\nNewer wings made of composite materials actually like to flex. They don\'t develop tiny cracks over time the way metal can, and they stay smooth and strong for decades.\n\n<b>The Bottom Line</b>\n\nThat gentle bending and rippling isn\'t a sign of stress — it\'s the wing doing its job exactly as designed. Every movement you see is energy that never reaches you.\n\nNext time you watch the wing flow and flex after landing, remember: everything is working perfectly. Those wings just turned a firm arrival into a smooth one.\n\nYou\'re witnessing sophisticated engineering in action — keeping your ride as comfortable and safe as possible.</string>

    <string name="landing_q3">Braking Systems Explained: Reverse Thrust, Autobrake, and Anti-Skid</string>
    <string name="landing_a3" formatted="false">The moment the wheels touch down, a whole orchestra of braking systems kicks in automatically. You feel a gentle push forward in your seat, you hear a roar from the engines, and the plane slows down smoothly and predictably. Nothing is left to chance – everything is designed, tested, and triple-redundant.\n\nHere\'s exactly what\'s happening and why you can completely relax.\n\n<b>1. Reverse Thrust – the loud roar that does most of the slowing at first</b>\n\nAs soon as the main wheels touch the runway, big doors (or sleeves) on the engines flip forward.\nThe engines still produce the same power, but now most of the air is blown forward instead of backward.\nIt\'s like opening a parachute behind a speeding car – you feel yourself pressed gently into the seat belt.\n\nModern engines are incredibly clever:\n• On Airbus aircraft, reverse thrust engages automatically the moment weight is on the wheels.\n• On Boeing, the pilot lifts the reverse levers, but the plane won\'t let them deploy in the air – a safety lock prevents it.\n• Usually only about 50–70% reverse power is used on dry runways (to save brakes and engines). In rain or on short runways, they can use full reverse.\n\nYou\'ll hear the roar fade away after 10–15 seconds because the plane is already slowing nicely.\n\n<b>2. Autobrake – the invisible co-pilot who does the braking for you</b>\n\nBefore landing, the pilots turn a knob to select one of five settings:\n• 1 or 2: gentle braking for long runways (you barely feel it)\n• 3: medium, most common on normal runways\n• MAX/AUTO MAX: very firm, used on short or slippery runways\n\nThe moment the wheels spin up (proving you\'re really on the ground), the autobrake applies exactly the right pressure to slow the plane at a steady, pre-chosen rate.\nIt\'s smoother and more consistent than even the best human pilot could manage, and it works together with anti-skid (see below).\nIf the pilots want to stop sooner, they simply press the brake pedals – autobrake instantly hands over control and disengages.\n\n<b>3. Anti-Skid – the system that makes skidding almost impossible</b>\n\nEvery main wheel has its own speed sensor. A computer watches all of them 20–40 times per second.\nIf one wheel starts slowing down much faster than the others (about to lock up on a wet or icy patch), the computer instantly releases that brake for a fraction of a second, then re-applies it – many times faster than a Formula 1 driver could.\n\nYou might feel a very slight pulsing or rumbling through the floor on a wet runway – that\'s anti-skid doing its job perfectly. It guarantees the plane stops in a straight line and uses every bit of available grip.\n\n<b>4. Extra layers of safety you never notice</b>\n\n• Even if all wheel brakes failed completely, reverse thrust alone can stop most jets on a normal runway.\n• If reverse thrust failed, the wheel brakes and anti-skid can easily stop the plane.\n• If both failed (almost unheard of), the runway still has thousands of metres of overrun area, and many have engineered material (EMAS) – a special crushable concrete that stops a plane gently.\n\n<b>5. Real numbers that calm the mind</b>\n\nA Boeing 737 landing at 140 knots (260 km/h) on a dry runway with autobrake 3 stops in about 35–40 seconds and uses roughly 1,600–1,800 metres.\nOn a soaking wet runway it might need 2,200–2,400 metres – and every major airport runway is at least that long (most are 3,000–4,000 m).\nThe pilots already calculated the exact distance needed before takeoff, and the runway has huge safety margins built in.\n\nSo when you feel that gentle push forward, hear the engines roar, and watch the runway lights slow down outside your window – everything is working exactly as it should.\nThree independent, computer-controlled systems are sharing the job, watching each other, and making sure you stop smoothly and safely every single time.\n\nYou\'re not relying on luck or a pilot stomping on the brakes.\nYou\'re being slowed by some of the most reliable technology ever built.</string>

    <string name="landing_q4">Landing in Heavy Rain – How Pilots See the Runway</string>
    <string name="landing_a4" formatted="false">When you look outside and see torrential rain streaking across the window, it\'s easy to wonder how the pilots can possibly see anything. The truth is: they don\'t need to see nearly as much as you think, and everything is built to work perfectly even in extremely low visibility conditions.\n\nHere\'s exactly how it works.\n\n<b>1. The runway lighting system is highly visible</b>\n\nModern runway edge lights, centreline lights, and approach lights are exceptionally bright and designed to cut through heavy rain:\n• They are visible from 5–8 km (3–5 miles) away even in a downpour.\n• They are spaced every 30–60 metres and colour-coded (white → amber → red) so pilots instantly know how far they are from the end.\n• Touchdown zone lights and high-intensity strobes guide the last few seconds.\n\n<b>2. Windshield wipers that actually work</b>\n\nAirliner wipers are nothing like your car\'s:\n• They sweep 2–3 times per second (faster than any road vehicle).\n• They are powered by hydraulic systems, not electric motors.\n• Many aircraft have an advanced hydrophobic rain-repellent coating that makes water bead and disperse instantly.\n• In extreme conditions, the pilot can activate a second layer of clear liquid repellent that spreads across the windshield.\n\n<b>3. The invisible highway in the sky: ILS and beyond</b>\n\nThe Instrument Landing System (ILS) is two radio beams:\n• One tells the plane if it\'s left or right of the centreline (the “localiser”).\n• One tells it if it\'s too high or too low (the “glideslope”).\n\nThese beams are accurate to within a few metres and work perfectly in any weather. On most flights, the autopilot follows them all the way down to 200 ft or lower. In really bad rain, the pilots can couple the autoland system and the plane flies itself to touchdown.\n\n<b>4. Head-Up Display (HUD) – advanced visual guidance</b>\n\nMany modern cockpits (especially Boeings) have a transparent screen in the pilot\'s direct line of sight:\n• A glowing green ladder and runway outline is projected onto the windshield.\n• Even if the real runway is barely visible through rain, the pilot sees a perfect virtual runway floating in front of them.\n• The HUD is so good that pilots can hand-fly a perfect approach in conditions where the windshield is almost opaque.\n\n<b>5. Wet runway performance – calculated to the metre</b>\n\nBefore every flight, the crew receives a detailed weather package. For rain they get:\n• Exact braking action reports from planes that landed minutes earlier (“braking action good/medium/poor”).\n• Precise water depth measurements if there\'s standing water.\n\nThey plug those numbers into an iPad or EFB (Electronic Flight Bag). The software tells them the exact runway distance needed – with huge safety margins. If the numbers don\'t add up, they divert long before they even start the approach. No guessing.\n\n<b>6. Grooved runways and special tyres</b>\n\nAlmost every major airport runway has thousands of tiny grooves cut into the surface (like the tread on a tyre). Water drains away instantly, so there\'s almost never a sheet of water to hydroplane on.\nAircraft tyres have deep grooves and are inflated to 200+ psi – they squeeze water out sideways like a squeegee.\n\n<b>7. The Reality</b>\n\nHydroplaning accidents on commercial jets are virtually unheard of in the last 30 years.\nIn the very rare event visibility drops below limits while on approach, the plane simply goes around automatically – exactly like in clear weather.\n\nEven in heavy rain with maximum wiper operation, pilots maintain full situational awareness.\nThey\'re following precision lighting and radio guidance, the runway drainage is functioning as designed, and multiple systems are verifying all parameters.\n\nYou\'re not landing "through" a storm.\nYou\'re following a precisely engineered approach that functions identically in all weather conditions.</string>

    <string name="landing_q5">Crosswind Landings: Why the Plane Flies Sideways</string>
    <string name="landing_a5" formatted="false">When the wind is blowing across the runway instead of straight down it, the approach and touchdown can look dramatic from your window. The plane might fly in at an angle, the nose pointed off to one side, and at the last second it straightens up. It looks unusual, but it\'s one of the most practiced and safest maneuvers pilots perform every day.\n\nHere\'s exactly what\'s happening and why it\'s completely under control.\n\n<b>1. Two techniques pilots use (often together)</b>\n\n• The Crab: High up on final approach, the pilot points the nose into the wind. The plane is flying sideways through the air, but the track over the ground stays perfectly lined up with the runway. From your seat it looks like the plane is drifting sideways; it\'s not. It\'s moving straight down the runway centerline.\n\n• The Wing-Low (or sideslip): As the plane gets lower, the pilot lowers one wing into the wind and uses opposite rudder to keep the nose pointed straight down the runway. This is the smooth ballet move you sometimes see.\n\nMost landings use a bit of both: crab on the way down, then transition to wing-low in the last 100–200 feet.\n\n<b>2. The "kick-out" or de-crab at the end</b>\n\nJust before the wheels touch, the pilot straightens the nose with rudder and levels the wings (or almost levels them).\nThat quick rudder movement is what makes the plane suddenly line up with the runway. It feels like a gentle bump or sway, nothing more.\nThe whole thing happens in 1–2 seconds and is practiced hundreds of times in the simulator.\n\n<b>3. The landing gear is built for sideways loads</b>\n\nThe main wheels and gear legs are deliberately designed to handle big side loads.\nThey can touch down with the plane drifting slightly sideways and absorb it without stress. On some aircraft (especially Boeing), the gear even tilts slightly on touchdown to make it smoother.\n\n<b>4. Real crosswind limits (what the plane can actually handle)</b>\n\nTypical maximum demonstrated crosswind components for common jets:\n• Boeing 737: 35–38 knots\n• Airbus A320 family: 38 knots\n• Boeing 777: 40–44 knots\n• Boeing 787 &amp; Airbus A350: 40–44 knots\n\nAirlines usually set their own limit 5–10 knots lower than that for extra comfort and safety.\nA 25–30 knot crosswind feels noticeable to passengers but is routine for crews; they land in it several times a week.\n\n<b>5. How pilots train for it</b>\n\nEvery six months pilots spend hours in the simulator practicing crosswind landings in 40-knot gusting winds, low visibility, wet runways, and even engine failures combined with crosswinds.\nThey have to prove they can land safely in the worst conditions the airline allows before they\'re allowed to fly passengers.\n\n<b>6. The Reality</b>\n\nThat sideways approach and last-second straightening isn\'t the pilot "fighting" the wind.\nIt\'s a deliberate, carefully taught technique that has been perfected over decades.\nThe plane is designed for it, the gear is designed for it, and the pilots have practiced it hundreds of times.\nWhat looks dramatic from row 23 is completely standard from the cockpit.\n\nNext time you see the plane flying in at an angle, remember: this is perfectly normal. Pilots perform this maneuver routinely and are extensively trained for it.</string>

    <string name="landing_q6">Fog and Low-Visibility Landings: How the Plane Lands When the Runway Is Invisible</string>
    <string name="landing_a6" formatted="false">When fog, heavy rain, or darkness swallows the runway, the aircraft switches to its most precise and safest mode: autoland. The plane follows two invisible radio beams broadcast from the runway (one for left/right guidance, one for height) that are accurate down to a few centimetres. These beams work perfectly no matter how thick the fog is.\n\nLong before you reach the airport, the crew checks the reported visibility. Most big airports today are equipped for Category III approaches, which means the plane can land with almost zero forward visibility (sometimes as little as 50 metres, sometimes none at all).\n\nHere\'s what happens:\n\n<b>1. Two or three independent autopilots are engaged at the same time.</b>\n\nThey constantly cross-check each other; if they disagree by even a tiny amount, the system instantly disconnects and the plane climbs away automatically for another try.\n\n<b>2. The autopilots fly the entire approach, flare, and touchdown.</b>\n\nThe flare (that gentle nose-up movement just before the wheels touch) happens at about 50 feet, and the landing is usually smoother than on a clear day because the computers react faster and more precisely than any human can.\n\n<b>3. After the wheels touch, the autobrakes and automatic rudder keep the plane exactly on the centreline.</b>\n\nThis continues until it\'s slow enough for the pilots to take over and taxi (many airports now have “follow-the-greens” taxiway lights that guide them through the fog).\n\nEverything is triple-redundant: radios, computers, hydraulics, electrical power. The system is designed so that even if one part fails, the landing continues safely.\n\nPilots train for this every six months in the simulator, and the technology has been in daily use for over fifty years with an impeccable safety record.\n\nSo when the world outside your window turns completely grey or white, nothing is wrong. The aircraft is now being flown with more precision, more redundancy, and less human input than on a bright sunny day.\n\nThe plane doesn\'t need to see the runway.\nIt knows exactly where it is, and it\'s taking you down perfectly.</string>

    <string name="landing_q7">Landing on Wet or Contaminated Runways: Why the Plane Still Stops</string>
    <string name="landing_a7" formatted="false">Rain, standing water, slush, or even a light dusting of snow doesn\'t turn a runway into an ice rink. Everything is measured, calculated, and backed by huge safety margins long before the wheels touch down.\n\nHere\'s how it really works.\n\n<b>1. Every time a plane lands ahead of you, the pilots send a short report: "braking action good", "medium", or "poor".</b>\n\nThose reports go instantly to every crew waiting to land, including yours.\n\n<b>2. Your pilots take those numbers and enter them into an iPad or onboard laptop.</b>: "braking action good", "medium", or "poor". Those reports go instantly to every crew waiting to land, including yours.\n\n2. Your pilots take those numbers (plus temperature, wind, and exact water/snow depth if reported) and enter them into an iPad or onboard laptop. In seconds the software tells them exactly how much runway they will need to stop, always with at least a 15–67 % extra safety margin required by law (67 % extra if the braking report is "poor").\n\nExample: a Boeing 737 on a perfectly dry 3,000-metre runway normally stops in about 1,500–1,800 metres. On a soaking wet runway with "medium" braking it might need 2,400 metres. Every major airport runway is at least 2,500–4,000 metres long, so there is still plenty left over.\n\nIf the numbers are even slightly too close, the pilots simply divert to another airport. They make that decision while still 200–300 miles out, not at the last second.\n\n3. The runway itself helps enormously. Almost all big airports have grooved or porous surfaces that drain water away instantly. A heavy rainstorm can dump buckets, yet within seconds the surface is almost dry again.\n\n4. The tyres are high-pressure (200+ psi) and have deep grooves that squeeze water sideways like a squeegee. Combined with anti-skid brakes that pulse 20–40 times per second, hydroplaning is practically impossible at normal landing speeds.\n\n5. In winter, runways are treated with de-icing liquids and swept constantly. If there\'s more than a thin layer of slush or snow, the airport closes the runway until it\'s cleared. Airlines won\'t land until it\'s officially safe.\n\nEven in the extremely rare worst-case where every brake failed (which has never happened on a modern jet), reverse thrust alone can stop the plane, and beyond the end of the runway there are usually 300–1,000 metres of clear safety area, plus crushable concrete beds (EMAS) at many airports that stop a plane gently if it ever overruns.\n\nSo when the runway outside looks shiny and wet, nothing is being left to chance.\nThe distance has already been calculated to the metre, the surface is engineered to drain instantly, and multiple independent braking systems are ready.\n\nThe plane will slow down and stop exactly where it always does, smoothly and predictably.</string>

    <string name="landing_q8">Thunderstorm Avoidance: Why Pilots Never Land in an Active Storm</string>
    <string name="landing_a8" formatted="false">Thunderstorms look dramatic from the ground, but from the cockpit they are treated with absolute respect. No commercial pilot will ever try to land in or near an active storm cell. Here\'s why, and how easily it\'s avoided.\n\n<b>1. Pilots can see thunderstorms long before you can</b>\n\nEvery airliner has a weather radar that paints storms in bright red and magenta up to 320 nautical miles (600 km) ahead. A single active cell stands out like a neon sign. Dispatchers on the ground also send updated radar pictures every few minutes.\n\n<b>2. The unbreakable rule: stay at least 20 nautical miles away</b>\n\nRegulations and airline policy require crews to stay 20 miles (37 km) sideways from any active thunderstorm (more if it\'s particularly intense). Above the storm, the distance increases to 5,000–10,000 ft vertically.\nThat distance is so large that lightning, hail, and severe turbulence almost never reach the aircraft.\n\n<b>3. Microbursts and wind shear are the real danger, and they\'re detected instantly</b>\n\nModern aircraft have predictive wind-shear systems that look 3–5 miles ahead. If the air suddenly changes direction or speed (a microburst), the cockpit speakers shout "WINDSHEAR! WINDSHEAR!" and the plane automatically applies full power and climbs.\nThese systems have prevented every single microburst accident since they became standard in the 1990s.\n\n<b>4. If a storm is sitting over the airport</b>\n\n• Flights hold in large racetrack patterns 50–100 miles away until the cell moves off (usually 20–40 minutes).\n• Or they divert to a planned alternate airport that was chosen before takeoff, with enough extra fuel for exactly this situation.\n• ATC clears entire corridors so no one has to fly near the storm.\n\n<b>5. Lightning is loud but harmless</b>\n\nAircraft are hit by lightning once or twice a year on average. The aluminium or carbon-fibre skin acts like a Faraday cage; the charge travels around the outside and exits through static wicks on the trailing edges. Passengers and systems inside are completely protected. The pre-flight walk-around checks for tiny entry/exit marks, and that\'s it.\n\n<b>The Reality</b>\n\nPilots will never attempt to "thread the needle" between storm cells to land. If the radar shows red anywhere near the final approach path, the crew diverts to another airport.\n\nHolding for weather or landing at an alternate airport is routine—crews treat it as a standard operational procedure.\n\nWhen you hear the captain say "we\'re just going to hold for a few minutes while a storm cell clears the area" or "we\'ll be diverting to our alternate," know that the system is working exactly as it should, keeping you far away from the one type of weather aviation always treats with zero tolerance.</string>

    <string name="landing_q9">Can We Hit a Building or Mountain When Flying in Clouds or Fog?</string>
    <string name="landing_a9">Short answer: No. Not even close.\n\nHere\'s why it\'s actually impossible on a commercial flight.\n\n<b>1. The plane always knows exactly where it is</b>\n\nModern airliners use triple GPS + inertial navigation systems that are accurate to within a few metres, even if every satellite disappeared.\nThese systems never drift more than a couple of hundred metres even after flying across the Atlantic with zero outside references.\n\n<b>2. The ground is mapped in 3D</b>\n\nEvery aircraft carries an Enhanced Ground-Proximity Warning System (EGPWS) with a worldwide terrain and obstacle database.\nIt knows the height and exact location of every mountain, radio tower, and tall building on Earth.\nIf the plane ever gets within about 30 seconds of hitting anything, the cockpit blares "TERRAIN! TERRAIN! PULL UP!" and a big red warning flashes. The system has saved hundreds of flights.\n\n<b>3. Air traffic control has multiple safety nets</b>\n\n• Controllers see your exact position and altitude on radar.\n• Their Minimum Safe Altitude Warning (MSAW) system automatically alerts them if you descend below a safe height for your location.\n• In busy areas, TCAS (the anti-collision system) will tell you to climb or descend if you ever get near high ground, even if everyone else somehow missed it.\n\n<b>4. Departure and arrival paths are drawn far above obstacles</b>\n\nEvery published route and approach is designed to keep you at least 1,000 ft (often 2,000–5,000 ft) above the highest obstacle or terrain within 10–25 miles.\nIn mountainous areas the minimum altitudes are much higher (sometimes 10,000–15,000 ft above the peaks).\n\n<b>5. In clouds or fog the plane is usually on autopilot following a pre-programmed path</b>\n\nThat path was designed years ago by engineers who triple-checked it against every hill and building.\nThe autopilot flies it with far more precision than any human could.\n\n<b>6. Real-life proof</b>\n\nSince EGPWS became mandatory in the early 2000s, there has not been a single passenger jet accident worldwide caused by flying into terrain in clouds or fog on a properly flown approach or departure.\n\nSo when the clouds are thick and you can\'t see anything outside, the plane is actually being guided by some of the most accurate and redundant navigation systems ever built.\nMountains and buildings are mapped, monitored, and avoided by multiple independent layers of technology and procedure.\n\nYou\'re surrounded by multiple independent layers of safety that make it virtually impossible to get anywhere near terrain.\nIn clouds or fog, you\'re often safer than on a clear day, because the automation and safeguards are operating with maximum precision.\n\nThe navigation and terrain avoidance systems ensure continuous safe separation from all obstacles.</string>

    <!-- Safety Facts Screen -->
    <string name="safety_title">Safety Facts</string>
    <string name="safety_subtitle">Why Flying Is One of the Safest Ways to Travel</string>
    <string name="safety_stat_passengers_title">5 Billion</string>
    <string name="safety_stat_passengers_desc">Passengers flew safely in 2024</string>
    <string name="safety_stat_flights_title">40 Million+</string>
    <string name="safety_stat_flights_desc">Flights operated worldwide</string>
    <string name="safety_stat_daily_title">109,589</string>
    <string name="safety_stat_daily_desc">Flights every single day</string>
    <string name="safety_stat_accident_rate_title">1 in 885,000</string>
    <string name="safety_stat_accident_rate_desc">Accident rate per flight (1.13 per million)</string>
    <string name="safety_stat_fatal_title">Only 7</string>
    <string name="safety_stat_fatal_desc">Fatal accidents in 2024 (out of 40M flights)</string>
    <string name="safety_stat_improvement_title">70%% Better</string>
    <string name="safety_stat_improvement_desc">Safety improved since 2005</string>
    <string name="safety_years_title">15,871 Years</string>
    <string name="safety_years_desc">You\'d have to fly every day for this long to statistically face a fatal accident</string>
    <string name="safety_comparison_title">Flights vs. Accidents (2024)</string>
    <string name="safety_comparison_flights">40,000,000 flights</string>
    <string name="safety_comparison_accidents">45 total accidents</string>
    <string name="safety_bottom_message">You\'re statistically safer in the air than driving to the airport. The skies have your back!</string>

    <!-- Learn Section Image Titles -->
    <string name="img_title_bird_strike_test">Bird Strike Testing with Chicken Gun</string>
    <string name="img_title_wing_flex">Boeing 787 Wing Flex Test</string>
    <string name="img_title_crosswind_landing">A380 Crosswind Landing</string>
    <string name="img_title_airport_lights">Airport Runway Lighting System</string>
    <string name="img_title_deicing">De-icing an Airbus A330</string>
    <string name="img_title_ils">ILS Localizer System</string>
    <string name="img_title_rat">RAM Air Turbine (RAT) on A320</string>

    <!-- Acceptance Meditation -->
    <string name="am_title">Acceptance Meditation</string>
    <string name="am_intro">This meditation uses acceptance-based principles to help you work with flight anxiety rather than fighting against it. It takes about 5-7 minutes and can be done before or during your flight.\n\nFind a comfortable position in your seat. You can keep your eyes open or gently closed—whatever feels right for you.</string>
    <string name="am_step_1">Grounding in the Present\n\nBegin by noticing three things you can see around you. The seat in front of you. The window. A light above.\n\nNow notice two things you can physically feel. Your feet on the floor. Your back against the seat.\n\nNotice one sound you can hear right now. The hum of the cabin. Voices nearby. The air system.\n\nTake a slow breath in... and out. You\'re here. You\'re present. That\'s all you need to be right now.</string>
    <string name="am_step_2">Acknowledging What\'s Here\n\nNotice if there\'s any anxiety in your body right now. You don\'t need to change it or push it away. Just notice where you feel it.\n\nMaybe it\'s in your chest. Your stomach. Your shoulders. Your throat.\n\nSay to yourself, silently: "This is anxiety. It\'s here right now."\n\nYou don\'t have to like it. You don\'t have to want it. You\'re simply acknowledging: this is what\'s present.\n\nAnxiety is uncomfortable, but it\'s not dangerous. It\'s your body trying to protect you, even though you don\'t need protection right now. Your body is doing what it evolved to do.</string>
    <string name="am_step_3">Making Room\n\nImagine your anxiety as an object. What shape would it be? What color? What size?\n\nNow imagine making a little more space around it. Not pushing it away—just allowing it to be there while you expand the space around it.\n\nBreathe into that space. Breathe around the anxiety, not against it.\n\nSay to yourself: "I can feel this anxiety and still be here. I can feel this discomfort and still take this flight."\n\nNotice: you\'ve felt anxiety before. Many times. And you\'re still here. Anxiety is temporary. It rises, peaks, and passes. Always.</string>
    <string name="am_step_4">Connecting with Your Values\n\nWhy are you taking this flight? What matters to you on the other side?\n\nMaybe you\'re seeing someone you love. Maybe you\'re building your career. Maybe you\'re expanding your world. Maybe you\'re simply refusing to let fear make your decisions.\n\nWhatever your reason: that is bigger than this temporary discomfort.\n\nSay to yourself: "I\'m willing to feel this anxiety because [your reason] matters to me."\n\nYou\'re not getting rid of the anxiety to take this flight. You\'re taking this flight with the anxiety. That\'s courage. That\'s what courage actually is—not the absence of fear, but action in the presence of fear.</string>
    <string name="am_step_5">Returning to the Breath\n\nBring your attention back to your breathing. Not changing it, just noticing it.\n\nBreath coming in. Breath going out.\n\nYour body knows how to breathe. Your body knows how to be here. Trust it.\n\nIf your mind wanders to worried thoughts, that\'s okay. Minds worry—that\'s what they do. Notice the thought, like a cloud passing by, and gently return to your breath.\n\nIn... and out. In... and out.</string>
    <string name="am_step_6">Closing\n\nYou don\'t need to be calm to fly. You don\'t need to enjoy flying. You just need to be willing to be here, with whatever feelings arise.\n\nAnxiety might come and go throughout this flight. Each time it appears, you can return to this: "I can feel this and still be here."\n\nTake one more deep breath.\n\nYou\'re doing something hard. You\'re doing it anyway. That matters.\n\nWhen you\'re ready, bring your awareness back to the cabin, knowing you can return to this practice anytime you need it.\n\nRemember: The goal isn\'t to eliminate anxiety—it\'s to change your relationship with it. You\'re learning that you can fly even when anxiety is present, and that\'s a powerful realization.</string>
    <!-- Help Options Screen -->
    <string name="help_options_title">Help Options</string>
    <string name="help_option_gforce_title">G-Force Monitor</string>
    <string name="help_option_gforce_desc">Monitor the turbulence in real-time. Seeing the actual G-force values can help you realize that the plane is stable and safe.</string>
    <string name="help_option_rtw_title">Riding the Wave</string>
    <string name="help_option_rtw_desc">Guided assistance to help you ride out a panic attack. Follow the steps to regain control and calm down.</string>
    <string name="help_option_ptw_title">Postpone the Worry</string>
    <string name="help_option_ptw_desc">Learn to set aside your worries for a later time. This technique helps you focus on the present moment.</string>
    <string name="help_option_wo_title">Worry Olympics</string>
    <string name="help_option_wo_desc">Challenge your catastrophic thinking. Evaluate how likely your worst fears really are.</string>
    <string name="help_option_ftf_title">Facing the Fear</string>
    <string name="help_option_ftf_desc">Confront your fears gradually. A structured approach to desensitization.</string>
    <string name="help_option_rc_title">Reality Check</string>
    <string name="help_option_rc_desc">Check the facts about flying safety. Reassure yourself with logic and data.</string>
    <string name="help_option_sf_title">Safety Facts</string>
    <string name="help_option_sf_desc">Learn about the safety mechanisms of modern aviation. Knowledge is power against fear.</string>
    <string name="help_option_am_title">Acceptance Meditation</string>
    <string name="help_option_am_desc">Practice accepting your feelings without judgment. A meditation to find peace amidst anxiety.</string>
    
    <!-- Updated SOS Content -->
    <string name="sos_help_options_title">HELP OPTIONS</string>
    <string name="sos_help_options_subtitle">See how this app can help you</string>

    <!-- Self-Compassion Tool -->
    <string name="sca_title">Self-Compassion</string>
    <string name="sca_intro">When anxiety or panic shows up, we usually respond with more fear. We judge ourselves for being anxious, criticize ourselves for not being braver, and fight against our own feelings. This meditation teaches you a different way—meeting your fear with kindness instead of judgment.\n\nSelf-compassion isn\'t about getting rid of anxiety. It\'s about changing how you relate to yourself when you\'re struggling. Research shows that self-compassion actually reduces anxiety more effectively than self-criticism does. Let\'s practice together.</string>
    
    <string name="sca_step_1">Find a comfortable position in your seat. Place one hand on your heart and one hand on your belly if that feels okay. If that feels too vulnerable right now, just rest your hands wherever they\'re comfortable.\n\nTake a slow breath in... and out. Good.\n\nNotice that you\'re anxious right now. You don\'t need to hide it or pretend it\'s not there. Anxiety is present. Fear is here. That\'s okay. You\'re not doing anything wrong by feeling this way.</string>
    
    <string name="sca_step_2">Your body is actually trying to help you right now. I know it doesn\'t feel like help—it feels terrible. But your body thinks you\'re in danger, and it\'s doing exactly what it evolved to do: trying to protect you, trying to get you ready to escape, trying to keep you safe.\n\nYour heart is racing because your body wants to help you run. Your breathing is quick because your body wants to give you oxygen. It\'s not broken. It\'s not betraying you. It\'s just... confused about what\'s actually dangerous. And that\'s okay. You can thank your body for trying to protect you, even if the protection isn\'t needed right now.</string>
    
    <string name="sca_step_3">Right now, thousands of people around the world are feeling exactly what you\'re feeling. Anxiety on planes is one of the most common fears humans have. You\'re not alone in this. You\'re not broken. You\'re not weak. You\'re having a completely normal human experience.\n\nPlace your attention on your heart, beneath your hand. Imagine breathing directly into that space. Breathing into the fear, into the tightness, into whatever is there.</string>
    
    <string name="sca_step_4">Now I want you to say something to yourself. You can say it silently in your mind, or whisper it if you\'re alone. Say: "This is really hard right now."\n\nThat\'s it. No fixing, no solving. Just acknowledgment. This is hard. You\'re allowed to find this hard.\n\nTake another breath. And now say: "I\'m not alone in feeling this way."\n\nBecause you\'re not. Right now, someone else on this plane might be anxious too. Someone in another airport is gripping their armrest. Someone else is taking deep breaths and trying to stay calm. You\'re part of the human family of people who sometimes feel afraid. There\'s no shame in that.</string>
    
    <string name="sca_step_5">Breathe in... and out. Feel your hand on your heart. That\'s you, offering yourself comfort. You\'re here for yourself right now.\n\nNow say: "May I be kind to myself in this moment."\n\nNot "may I calm down" or "may I stop being anxious." Just... may I be kind to myself.\n\nImagine for a moment that there\'s a small child sitting next to you. Maybe five or six years old. And this child is scared. Really scared. Their eyes are wide, their hands are trembling, they\'re trying so hard to be brave but they\'re terrified.\n\nWhat would you do? You\'d probably put your arm around them. You\'d speak softly. You\'d say, "I know, sweetheart. I know you're scared. It\'s okay to be scared. I\'ve got you. You\'re safe with me."\n\nYou wouldn\'t tell that child to toughen up. You wouldn\'t shame them for being afraid. You\'d just... hold them. Comfort them. Let them know they\'re not alone.\n\nThat scared child is you. The part of you that\'s anxious right now is that little kid who needs someone to say, "I\'ve got you. You\'re not alone."</string>
    
    <string name="sca_step_6">Can you be that person for yourself? Can you imagine wrapping your arms around that scared part of you and saying, "I know this is scary. I\'m here with you. You\'re safe with me"?\n\n"I know this is scary. I\'m here with me. I\'m doing okay."\n\nTake a breath. Feel your hand on your heart, warm and steady. That\'s you, being your own friend. That\'s you, showing up for yourself.\n\nAnxiety might still be here. That\'s okay. You don\'t need to make it go away to be kind to yourself. You can feel afraid and still deserve compassion. You can be anxious and still be worthy of care.\n\nSay: "May I accept myself exactly as I am right now."\n\nNot who you wish you were. Not some calm, fearless version of you. The you that\'s here right now, with whatever feelings are present. That version of you deserves kindness.</string>
    
    <string name="sca_step_7">Breathe. Your hand on your heart is an anchor. It\'s a reminder: I am here. I care about myself. I\'m not abandoning myself in this hard moment.\n\nNotice if your inner voice has softened even a little. Notice if there\'s a bit more space around the anxiety. You\'re not fighting yourself anymore. You\'re with yourself.\n\nThink about what you need right now. Not what you think you should need, but what would actually help. Maybe it\'s someone to talk to. Maybe it\'s to close your eyes. Maybe it\'s to look out the window. Maybe it\'s just to keep breathing and know that you\'re doing the best you can.\n\nWhatever you need, see if you can give yourself permission to have it. You\'re allowed to need support. You\'re allowed to struggle. You\'re allowed to be imperfect and human.\n\nSay: "I am doing the best I can. That is enough."\n\nBecause you are. You showed up for this flight even though you\'re afraid. You\'re trying to work with your anxiety instead of just white-knuckling through it. You\'re reading this, practicing this, trying to take care of yourself. That matters. That takes courage.\n\nTake one more deep breath. Feel your hand on your heart, that warm pressure, that reminder that you\'re here for yourself.\n\nThe anxiety might not be gone. That\'s okay. You\'re not trying to make it disappear. You\'re just trying to be a little kinder to yourself while it\'s here. And that changes everything.\n\nYou can return to this practice anytime. Anytime you notice you\'re being harsh with yourself, anytime you\'re judging your fear, you can come back to your hand on your heart and these simple words: "This is hard. I\'m not alone. May I be kind to myself."\n\nYou\'re doing beautifully. I mean that. The fact that you\'re here, trying, working with yourself instead of against yourself—that\'s something to be proud of.\n\nGently remove your hand from your heart when you\'re ready. Take one more breath. You\'ve just practiced something powerful: meeting your fear with friendship instead of criticism.\n\nCarry that with you.</string>

    <string name="help_option_sca_title">Self-Compassion</string>
    <string name="help_option_sca_desc">Learn to meet your fear with kindness instead of judgment. A guided practice to soothe your inner critic.</string>
</resources>
