<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CalmFlight</string>

    <!-- General -->
    <string name="previous">Previous</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="continue_btn">Continue</string>
    <string name="finish_btn">Finish</string>
    <string name="close_btn">Close</string>
    <string name="start_flight_btn">Start Flight</string>
    <string name="end_flight_btn">End Flight</string>
    <string name="cancel_btn">Cancel</string>

    <!-- Flight Mode Dialogs -->
    <string name="flight_start_title">Your flight is about to start</string>
    <string name="flight_start_question">How bad/scary do you expect it to be?</string>
    <string name="flight_end_title">Welcome back!</string>
    <string name="flight_end_question">You are about to end the flight. How bad/scary was the flight actually?</string>
    <string name="flight_mode_active">Flight Mode Active</string>
    <string name="flight_mode_inactive">Start Flight Mode</string>

    <!-- Navigation -->
    <string name="nav_cockpit">Cockpit</string>
    <string name="nav_learn">Learn</string>
    <string name="nav_sos">SOS</string>
    <string name="nav_tools">Tools</string>

    <!-- Cockpit Screen -->
    <string name="cockpit_title">Cockpit</string>
    <string name="g_force_monitor">G-FORCE MONITOR</string>
    <string name="safe_operating_zone">Safe Zone</string>
    <string name="perfectly_safe">You are perfectly safe.</string>
    <string name="immediate_intervention">IMMEDIATE INTERVENTION</string>
    <string name="breathe_with_me_desc">Breathe with me.\nInhale... Exhale...</string>
    <string name="all_systems_normal">All systems\nnormal.</string>
    <string name="cruising_smoothly">We are cruising smoothly.\nFlight deck is calm.</string>
    <string name="calm_flight_desc">Calm flight</string>
    
    <!-- Cockpit Phases Content -->
    <string name="boarding_title">Getting Ready</string>
    <string name="boarding_desc">The anticipation is often worse than the flight itself. Use these tools to quiet your mind before takeoff.</string>
    <string name="takeoff_tools_title">Takeoff Tools</string>
    <string name="cruise_tools_title">Cruise Tools</string>
    <string name="landing_tools_title">Landing Tools</string>
    <string name="tool_shortcut_desc_ptw">Schedule your worry for later instead of fighting it now.</string>
    <string name="tool_shortcut_desc_wo">Exaggerate your fears until they become ridiculous.</string>
    <string name="tool_shortcut_desc_rtw">Feeling panic rising? Ride the adrenaline wave.</string>
    <string name="tool_shortcut_desc_rtw_landing">Handle descent sensations and bumps.</string>
    <string name="tool_shortcut_desc_ftf">Examine your sensations with curiosity.</string>

    <!-- Weather Widget -->
    <string name="weather_widget_title">Flight Conditions</string>
    <string name="weather_check_btn">Check Local Weather</string>
    <string name="weather_permission_hint">Grant location access to see takeoff conditions.</string>
    <string name="weather_loading">Loading weather data...</string>
    <string name="weather_error_generic">Could not load weather data.</string>
    <string name="weather_error_offline">No internet connection. You might be in Flight Mode already!</string>
    <string name="weather_offline_reassurance">Don\'t worry. Pilots have the latest weather data directly in the cockpit.</string>
    <string name="weather_wind_fmt">Wind: %.1f km/h</string>
    <string name="weather_msg_excellent">Conditions are excellent. Expect a smooth takeoff.</string>
    <string name="weather_msg_breezy">It\'s a bit breezy (%.1f km/h). You might feel some bumps, but it\'s completely safe.</string>
    <string name="weather_msg_cloudy">It\'s cloudy or raining. The takeoff might be a little bumpy, but pilots do this every day.</string>

    <!-- G-Force Monitor -->
    <string name="status_smooth">SMOOTH FLIGHT</string>
    <string name="status_light_bumps">LIGHT BUMPS</string>
    <string name="status_moderate">MODERATE CHOP</string>
    <string name="status_bumpy">BUMPY (SAFE)</string>
    <string name="gforce_explanation_title">About this Monitor</string>
    <string name="gforce_explanation">This tool uses your phone\'s accelerometer to measure real-time G-Forces. Commercial planes are built to withstand extreme forces (-1.0G to +2.5G), far beyond what you experience in even the worst turbulence.\n\nPlace your phone flat on a tray table or armrest for best results.</string>
    <string name="gforce_safe_range">Normal Safe Range: -1.0G - 2.5G</string>
    <string name="gforce_current_label">Current</string>
    <string name="gforce_min_label">Min</string>
    <string name="gforce_max_label">Max</string>

    <!-- Flight Status -->
    <string name="status_on_land">On Land</string>
    <string name="status_boarding">Boarding</string>
    <string name="status_takeoff">Takeoff</string>
    <string name="status_cruise">Cruise</string>
    <string name="status_turbulence">Turbulence</string>
    <string name="status_landing">Landing</string>

    <!-- On Land Widget -->
    <string name="on_land_card_title">Ready to fly?</string>
    <string name="on_land_card_desc">Tap the button below to start Flight Mode. You can log your anxiety levels before and after the flight to track your progress.</string>

    <!-- Learn Screen -->
    <string name="search_questions">Search questions...</string>
    <string name="search_desc">Search</string>

    <!-- SOS Screen -->
    <string name="pause_and_listen">PAUSE &amp; LISTEN</string>
    <string name="pilot_voice_msg">Pilot Voice: \"You are safe. The plane is flying normally. Focus on your feet...\"</string>
    <string name="exit_sos_mode">EXIT SOS MODE</string>
    <string name="breathe_in">Breathe In</string>
    <string name="hold">Hold</string>
    <string name="breathe_out">Breathe Out</string>
    
    <!-- New SOS Content -->
    <string name="sos_panic_title">I\'M PANICKING\nRIGHT NOW</string>
    <string name="sos_panic_subtitle">My body is shaking or I can\'t breathe</string>
    <string name="sos_turbulence_title">THE PLANE IS\nSCARING ME</string>
    <string name="sos_turbulence_subtitle">It\'s bumpy, noisy, or feels wrong</string>
    <string name="sos_help_message">What is happening right now?</string>

    <!-- Tools Screen -->
    <string name="tools_title">Tools</string>

    <!-- Riding The Wave Tool -->
    <string name="rtw_title">Riding the Wave</string>
    <string name="rtw_intro">You\'re having a panic attack right now and thinking \"Why should I trust this?\". Here\'s why you can trust it: every panic attack you\'ve ever had - even the ones where you were 100% sure you were dying - ended all by itself.\n\nThat\'s because panic is a surge of adrenaline, and your body simply cannot keep pumping it out forever. It always runs out of fuel and the attack stops, usually within 4-10 minutes at most.\n\n\"Riding the wave\" is one of the main skills taught in Dialectical Behavior Therapy (DBT), a treatment used in hospitals and clinics all over the world for intense panic and emotions. People who learn to stop fighting the feelings finish their panic attacks much faster - often in half the time or less - and have fewer attacks overall.\n\nFighting the wave (\"Make it stop!\") keeps it going for 20-40 minutes. Letting it rise and fall turns it into a 3-5 minute rough patch instead. This isn\'t wishful thinking; it\'s how your body actually works, and thousands of people just like you have proved it.\n\nYou\'re about to prove it too.</string>
    
    <string name="rtw_step_1">Your heart is pounding. Your chest feels tight. You feel dizzy or unreal. That\'s okay. This is just a wave of adrenaline - it feels awful, but it CANNOT hurt you and it ALWAYS ends. Every single panic attack you\'ve ever had has stopped on its own. This one will too - faster if you stop fighting it.</string>
    <string name="rtw_step_2">Right now, put your phone down for a second and say inside your head:\n\n\"Okay, here it comes. It\'s just the wave.\"</string>
    <string name="rtw_step_3">Don\'t try to slow your breathing. Don\'t try to calm down. Don\'t fight any feeling. Let your heart race as fast as it wants. Let your hands shake. Let the dizziness be there. You are allowing everything to happen exactly as it is.</string>
    <string name="rtw_step_4">Silently tell your body:\n\n\"Go ahead - do your worst. I\'m not going to stop you.\"</string>
    <string name="rtw_step_5">Notice where you feel it most - chest, stomach, throat? Just watch it like you\'re watching a wave at the beach. You don\'t have to like it, you only have to let it be there.</string>
    <string name="rtw_step_6">Keep watching. In a moment you\'ll feel the first tiny drop - maybe your shoulders loosen a bit or the tightness eases just a little. That\'s the wave starting to crash.</string>
    <string name="rtw_step_7">Stay with it. The peak is passing right now. It\'s already going down, even if it doesn\'t feel calm yet.</string>
    <string name="rtw_step_8">You\'re doing it. You\'re riding it instead of drowning in it. A few more breaths and it will keep falling.</string>
    <string name="rtw_step_9">There... feel that? It\'s getting smaller. You\'re safe. The wave is leaving all by itself - because you let it.</string>
    <string name="rtw_step_10">You did it. It\'s over much sooner than if you had fought.\n\nNext time it will be even shorter. You\'ve just proved you can ride any wave.</string>

    <!-- Postpone The Worry Tool -->
    <string name="ptw_title">Postpone the Worry</string>
    <string name="ptw_intro">You\'re thinking: \"Just delay it? That can\'t possibly work.\" It feels too simple, but it\'s one of the most powerful tools in Metacognitive Therapy, the treatment that has been shown in research to reduce anxiety faster and more lastingly than traditional methods.\n\nYour brain treats every scary thought as an urgent problem that must be solved immediately. In a plane, that\'s useless: there is nothing you can do about the wings or the engines right now. Keeping the worry running for hours only exhausts you.\n\nThe trick is to give the worry an official, specific time later - so your mind accepts that the job is safely scheduled and stops pressing the alarm button.</string>
    
    <string name="ptw_step_1">Do this right now:\n\nSay to yourself (quietly or in your head):\n\n\"All worrying and what-if thoughts about the flight are now officially postponed until the very last minute of this flight, just before we land.\"</string>
    <string name="ptw_step_2">Whenever another scary thought appears, answer it with the exact same sentence:\n\n\"Thank you. Postponed until the final minute.\"</string>
    <string name="ptw_step_3">That\'s all. No fighting, no arguing, no reassuring yourself the plane is safe. Just postpone.</string>
    <string name="ptw_step_4">Most people notice the pressure drop within 30-60 seconds because the brain no longer believes the worry is needed right now.</string>
    <string name="ptw_step_5">And here\'s what almost always happens: when that final minute actually arrives hours later, you\'ll look up and realise the worry feels tiny - or you won\'t even remember what you were going to worry about.</string>
    <string name="ptw_step_6">Either way, you will have given yourself hours of calm instead of hours of torment.\n\nPostpone it. You haven\'t lost anything, and you\'ve just reclaimed the rest of your flight.</string>

    <!-- Worry Olympics Tool -->
    <string name="wo_title">Worry Olympics</string>
    <string name="wo_intro">Therapists use this exact method because when you try - with total commitment - to scare yourself even worse on purpose, your brain almost always goes \"Wait... this is ridiculous\" and the panic collapses into laughter or relief in seconds.\n\nDo it right now. Follow every step exactly:</string>
    
    <string name="wo_step_1">Step 1: What You\'re Actually Thinking Right Now\n\nClose your eyes. Don\'t fight it-lean into it. Mentally catalogue the \"evidence\" your anxiety is presenting:\n\n\"That rattle is new. We just dropped 200 feet, I felt it. The wing is bending way too much. Pilot hasn\'t spoken in 8 minutes-he\'s either dead or too busy fighting the controls to talk. Flight attendant smiled too wide; that\'s reassurance masking panic. I should have driven.\"</string>
    <string name="wo_step_2">Step 2: Give Your Fear the Microphone\n\nImagine standing up, grabbing the intercom, and delivering-dead serious-what your nervous system is screaming:\n\n\"Ladies and gentlemen, passenger in 22B. I have updates. That vibration is not normal turbulence; it\'s a harmonic imbalance in the port engine. The wing is flexing beyond manufacturer specs-I\'ve been watching it. The pilot\'s silence is now at 11 minutes, which in aviation time is roughly forever. Also, the coffee tasted off, which is probably hydraulic fluid contamination. I have no formal flight training, but I\'ve consumed every air crash investigation documentary ever made, and I am qualified to say: we should be panicking. Please panic in an orderly fashion.\"</string>
    <string name="wo_step_3">Step 3: What Passengers Are Actually Thinking\n\nLook around.\n\nThe guy next to you: \"Did I close the garage door?\"\n\nThe woman across the aisle: \"Why is the Wi-Fi $8 for 30 minutes? This is theft.\"\n\nKid behind you: \"My iPad is at 3% and this plane has no outlets. My life is over.\"\n\nFlight attendant: \"If one more person asks me about the chicken or pasta option, I\'m quitting.\"</string>
    <string name="wo_step_4">Step 4: Abruptly Yell \"CUT!\"\n\nOpen your eyes. Same engine hum. Same wing flex. Same plane. The only thing that crashed was the story you were telling yourself-because once you voiced it aloud (even just mentally), your brain heard how absurd it sounds.</string>
    <string name="wo_step_5">What Just Happened?\n\nYou caught the fear red-handed, scripting the disaster. You were the narrator, not the passenger. And narrators can change the channel.</string>

    <!-- Facing The Fear Tool -->
    <string name="ftf_title">Facing the Fear</string>
    <string name="ftf_intro">For right now, when the panic feels huge and solid.\n\nSit back, keep your eyes open or closed-whatever feels okay.\n\nWe\'re going to fly straight into the middle of this scary feeling, like a pilot flying into a dark cloud that looks terrifying from far away. Everyone knows that when the plane actually enters the cloud, there\'s nothing there-just soft mist. Let\'s do the same with this emotion.</string>
    
    <string name="ftf_step_1">Start by noticing the feeling as a whole. From a little distance it looks black, heavy, dangerous. That\'s normal. Now we\'re going to get closer, the way a scientist would, curious instead of scared.\n\nFind the strongest part of the feeling right now. Where is it exactly?\n\nMaybe a tight band around your chest, or pressure in your throat, or a swirling in your stomach. Put your attention gently on that spot. Don\'t push it away-just look.</string>
    <string name="ftf_step_2">Ask the feeling, quietly: \"Where are your edges?\"\n\nClouds always look solid from afar, but up close they have no hard border. Is this feeling sharp and solid, or is it actually fuzzy, changing, moving the moment you try to grab it?</string>
    <string name="ftf_step_3">Notice your heart beating fast.\n\nWhen you run for the bus or go up the stairs quickly, your heart races even harder than this-and you don\'t mind at all. What\'s the difference right now?\n\nOnly the story that says \"fast heart = danger.\" Without that story, it\'s just a heart doing its job.</string>
    <string name="ftf_step_4">Now zoom in even closer, like putting the feeling under a microscope.\n\nIs the tightness in your chest actually painful, or is it just pressure?\n\nIs the dizziness really the world spinning, or is it a light, floaty sensation with a scary label stuck on it?</string>
    <string name="ftf_step_5">Keep breathing normally and ask: \"If I didn\'t call this feeling \'panic,\' what would it be?\"\n\nA warm wave? Energy moving? A tingling?\n\nMost people discover it\'s just ordinary body sensations wearing a monster mask.</string>
    <string name="ftf_step_6">Look for the scariest part again. Where did it go?\n\nThe closer you get, the more it dissolves. Just like a real cloud-there\'s no dark centre, no monster hiding inside. Only soft, passing mist.</string>
    <string name="ftf_step_7">Stay here for a few more breaths.\n\nNothing to fix, nothing to fight. You\'re flying right through the middle of the cloud and discovering there was never anything solid to crash into.</string>
    <string name="ftf_step_8">When you\'re ready, open your eyes or soften your gaze.\n\nThe feeling may still be around, but you\'ve seen the truth: it\'s made of the same harmless stuff as every other sensation-just clouds passing through an open sky.\n\nYou can always fly into any cloud and find the same thing: nothing there.</string>

    <string name="anxiety_level_label">Anxiety Level: %d/10</string>
    <string name="rate_btn">Rate</string>
    <string name="feedback_improving">It is getting better! Keep going.</string>
    <string name="feedback_worsening">Trust the process. It will pass.</string>
    <string name="feedback_steady">You are doing great. Ride the wave.</string>
    
    <string name="congrats_title">Well Done!</string>
    <string name="congrats_msg">You managed your panic attack successfully. Every time you ride the wave, it gets easier.</string>

    <!-- Learn Sections -->
    <string name="learn_section_takeoff">Takeoff &amp; Climbing</string>
    <string name="learn_section_landing">Landing</string>

    <!-- Takeoff Questions -->
    <string name="takeoff_q1">Why does the whole plane vibrate and rattle before it even moves?</string>
    <string name="takeoff_a1">You\'re sitting there, the engines are still quiet, and suddenly the entire cabin starts shaking, rattling, and buzzing like something is loose or broken. It feels wrong and scary.\n\nHere\'s exactly what\'s happening:\n\nWhile you\'re waiting at the gate or taxiing, the pilots and the ground crew are doing last-second checks. The biggest shake usually comes when the pilots turn on the hydraulic pumps at full power and test the flight controls (ailerons, elevators, rudder).\n\nThose big control surfaces on the wings and tail move quickly left-right and up-down. When they do, the hydraulic lines and actuators make the whole airframe vibrate and transmit the movement into the cabin. It\'s the same as when you test the steering wheel of a car hard left and right - the whole car shudders a little.\n\nYou might also hear a loud whining or barking sound under the floor. That\'s the PTU (Power Transfer Unit), a normal hydraulic system that makes a loud \"dog barking\" noise on many Airbus planes (and similar noises on Boeings). It only runs when one hydraulic system is at lower pressure - completely routine.\n\nSometimes the air-conditioning packs are switched from ground power to the engines or APU, and that makes the floor vibrate for a few seconds.\n\nAll of this happens before the plane even starts rolling and it is 100 %% normal. Pilots do it on every single flight. The plane is not falling apart - it\'s just waking up its muscles and making sure everything moves freely before the takeoff run. Nothing is loose, nothing is broken. It\'s the aviation version of stretching before a sprint.\n\nOnce the engines spool up and you start moving, most of that pre-flight rattling disappears.\n\nYou\'re perfectly safe - the plane is just saying \"systems checked and ready.\"</string>

    <string name="takeoff_q2">What are all those clicking and clunking noises right before we start rolling?</string>
    <string name="takeoff_a2">Those sounds are the flight control surfaces (ailerons, rudder, elevators) being tested, hydraulic systems pressurizing, and the parking brake releasing. Pilots run through a checklist that involves moving various parts - each click and clunk is a system confirming it\'s ready for flight.</string>

    <string name="takeoff_q3">That drop or dip right after takeoff - are we falling back down?</string>
    <string name="takeoff_a3">No, you\'re not falling. It feels exactly like the plane just lost all lift and is dropping, but it\'s actually a normal (and deliberate) maneuver that happens on almost every single takeoff.\n\nHere\'s precisely what\'s going on:\n\nAs soon as the wheels leave the ground, the pilot pulls the nose up to a steep climb angle (usually 15-20 degrees). That gives you the strong \"pushing you back in your seat\" feeling.\n\nA few seconds later, at around 35-100 feet above the runway, the pilot reduces engine power from full takeoff thrust to a lower \"climb thrust.\" This is required by law and airline rules to save the engines and reduce noise over the airport area. The sudden drop in engine roar makes it feel like the power just disappeared.\n\nAt almost the same moment, the pilot lowers the nose slightly (from 18 degrees to about 10-12 degrees) so the plane accelerates to a safe climbing speed. That small pitch-down movement creates the unmistakable \"elevator drop\" or \"sinking\" sensation in your stomach.\n\nOn top of that, the huge flaps that were hanging down for takeoff start retracting. When the first stage of flaps comes up, the wing temporarily loses a tiny bit of lift, which adds to the sinking feeling.\n\nAll of this happens in the space of 5-10 seconds, usually below 500 feet. It feels dramatic because you\'re very low and your body isn\'t used to it, but the plane is climbing the entire time (often at 2,000-3,000 feet per minute). The altimeter is going up, not down.\n\nPilots do this on every flight, every day, millions of times a year. It\'s not an emergency, it\'s not a mistake, and the plane is nowhere near stalling or falling.\n\nIt\'s just the normal \"clean-up\" phase after takeoff: reduce power -> lower the nose a little -> retract flaps -> settle into a steady climb.\n\nNext time you feel that dip, remind yourself: \"That\'s just the pilot shifting gears.\"\n\nIt always passes in seconds, and then the ride smooths out. You\'re climbing safely the whole time.</string>

    <string name="takeoff_q4">Why do the engines suddenly get quieter the moment we\'re in the air? Did they turn off?</string>
    <string name="takeoff_a4">The engines are still running at high power. What changed is the noise abatement procedure: pilots reduce thrust slightly after clearing obstacles to minimize noise over residential areas. The plane is still climbing safely. You\'ll hear power increase again once past noise-sensitive zones.</string>

    <string name="takeoff_q5">The plane is still wobbling and rocking side to side - shouldn\'t it feel stable immediately?</string>
    <string name="takeoff_a5">No, it\'s completely normal for the plane to wobble, rock, and sway for the first 1-3 minutes after takeoff - even on a clear day. It does not mean the pilots have lost control or that something is wrong.\n\nHere\'s exactly why it happens:\n\nYou\'re flying through the air that was just above the ground.\n\nThe first 500-2,000 feet are full of uneven heat rising off the runway, buildings, and parking lots. That warm air acts like invisible speed bumps - it makes the plane bobble and rock exactly the way a boat rocks on choppy water near the shore. Once you climb above that layer (usually within a minute or two), it smooths out dramatically.\n\nThe pilots are \"cleaning up\" the plane.\n\nIn the first minute they are retracting flaps and slats in stages. Every time a big flap moves up, the wing shape changes a little, and the plane gives a small roll or wiggle until the autopilot or pilot trims it out. It\'s like shifting gears in a car - there\'s a tiny lurch each time.\n\nLow-level wind is almost always uneven.\n\nClose to the ground the wind speed and direction change every few seconds (wind shear or gusts). At cruising altitude the wind is usually steady, but down low the plane gets pushed left-right a bit until it climbs into smoother air.\n\nThe autopilot usually isn\'t fully engaged yet.\n\nOn many flights the pilots hand-fly the first few hundred feet, or the autopilot is only in a basic mode. They let the plane rock a little while they finish checklists and set the proper climb mode. Once everything is set (often below 5,000 feet), it locks in and feels rock-solid.\n\nEvery professional pilot expects this low-altitude wobble - they call it the \"departure bounce\" or \"low-level junk.\"\n\nIf the plane went from runway to glass-smooth the instant the wheels left the ground, that would actually be unusual.\n\nYou\'ll feel it settle very soon - usually before the seat-belt sign goes off.\n\nThe rocking is proof you\'re climbing through the messy air near the airport, not proof that anything is wrong. Once you\'re above a couple thousand feet, you\'ll be in the calm layer and it will feel like a different aircraft. Just hang on for another minute or two - the smooth part is coming.</string>

    <string name="takeoff_q6">What if the engine fails during the takeoff?</string>
    <string name="takeoff_a6">This is the big one that keeps most nervous flyers awake at night. Here\'s the straight truth:\n\nIt almost never happens.\n\nModern jet engines are designed to run for 50,000-100,000 hours between major overhauls. The chance of one quitting exactly during takeoff is roughly 1 in 2-3 million flights. You are literally more likely to be struck by lightning twice in the same year.\n\nEven if it does happen, the plane is built for it.\n\nEvery commercial jet is certified to take off, climb safely, and return to land with only one engine (or even with all engines failed on some aircraft after a certain speed). That rule is non-negotiable; the plane would never be allowed to fly passengers if it couldn\'t do it.\n\nThere are two very clear phases:\n\nBefore V1 (the \"decision speed\" you hear pilots talk about):\n\nIf an engine fails here, the pilots simply abort the takeoff. They brake hard, stay on the runway, and stop with plenty of pavement left. That\'s why runways are extra long. This happens a few times a year worldwide and almost nobody ever gets hurt.\n\nAfter V1 (usually 20-40 seconds before the wheels leave the ground):\n\nThe plane is already going fast enough that stopping is no longer the safest option. The pilots keep going, lift off normally, climb away on the remaining engine(s), circle back, and land in 10-20 minutes - usually without even declaring an emergency. Passengers often don\'t notice anything except a slightly louder engine noise and a turn back to the airport.\n\nReal-life examples:\n\nQantas 32 (A380, 2010) - massive engine explosion right after takeoff from Singapore. They flew for almost two hours on the remaining three engines and landed safely.\n\nBritish Airways 2276 (Boeing 777, Las Vegas 2015) - left engine caught fire during takeoff roll. Crew rejected takeoff, everyone walked away in under 90 seconds.\n\nHundreds of similar events every decade - zero fatalities in modern jets when crews follow the rules (which they always do).\n\nThe pilots train for this exact scenario every six months in the simulator - sometimes twice a year. They practice engine failure at the worst possible moment dozens of times so it becomes routine.\n\nBottom line: an engine failure on takeoff is spectacularly unlikely, and even if it happens the plane and crew are 100 %% prepared.\n\nYou are safer than you have ever been in a car on the highway.\n\nIf you ever hear the engines go uneven or see the plane turning back shortly after takeoff, remind yourself: \"This is the thing they train for every six months - it\'s handled.\"\n\nThen sit back. You\'ll be on the ground drinking coffee in 15 minutes.</string>

    <string name="takeoff_q7">The runway is wet or snowy - is it safe to takeoff?</string>
    <string name="takeoff_a7">Yes, it is safe. Airlines and airports have strict rules, and they don\'t guess.\n\nHere\'s exactly how it works:\n\nThere are three official runway conditions:\nDry -> normal performance\nWet -> slightly longer stopping distance, but still perfectly safe\nContaminated (standing water, slush, ice, compacted snow) -> special numbers\n\nIf the runway is just wet (rain, light water on the surface), pilots use \"wet performance\" tables. They already add hundreds or thousands of extra feet to the required runway length. On a normal day they might need 6,000 ft; on a wet day they calculate for 7,500-8,000 ft. If the runway is shorter than that, they simply wait or reduce weight (take less fuel or passengers - which happens automatically).\n\nIf there is slush, ice or heavy snow:\n\nThe airport measures the depth and type every 30-60 minutes and sends an official report (called SNOWTAM or runway condition report).\n\nPilots get the latest numbers on their iPads seconds before pushback. The plane\'s computer then recalculates exactly how much runway is needed.\n\nIf it\'s too slippery or too short -> the flight does not depart. No discussion. Hundreds of flights get delayed or cancelled every winter for exactly this reason. They would rather delay you six hours than take even a tiny risk.\n\nExtra safety margins built in:\n\nEven the \"wet\" or \"contaminated\" calculations include a 15 %% safety buffer required by law. That means the plane will stop or get airborne with hundreds of metres to spare, even if everything is worse than measured.\n\nBraking systems and tyres:\n\nModern aircraft tyres have water-channel grooves (like car tyres), and the anti-skid brakes work even better on a wet surface than on dry (they pulse 20-30 times a second to prevent skidding).\n\nReverse thrust and spoilers work the same in rain or snow.\n\nReal-world proof: in Europe and North America, thousands of planes take off and land every day in rain, snow, and slush. Serious incidents caused purely by a wet or snowy runway are very rare in the last 30 years.\n\nBottom line: if your plane is cleared to take off in the rain or snow, it means the numbers have been checked three times (airport, pilots, aircraft computer) and there is a huge safety margin.\n\nIf it wasn\'t safe, you would still be sitting at the gate.\n\nThe pilots want to get home to their families just as much as you do.</string>

    <string name="takeoff_q8">What if we get hit by a bird during takeoff?</string>
    <string name="takeoff_a8">Bird strikes happen - about 40 times a day worldwide - but the nightmare scenario you\'re picturing (both engines exploding, plane crashing) is practically science fiction.\n\nHere\'s exactly what happens in real life:\n\nEngines are literally tested by firing dead chickens at them:\n\nBefore any jet engine is certified, the manufacturer has to shoot frozen 4-8 lb birds straight into a running engine at full takeoff power (using a chicken cannon). The engine must keep running or shut down safely without fire or uncontained blades flying out. They do this dozens of times. Your engines have already survived worse than any real bird you\'ll meet.\n\n99.9 %% of bird strikes do almost nothing:\nSmall birds -> get shredded, you might hear a thud or smell burnt chicken for a minute.\nBig birds (geese, gulls) -> louder bang, possible vibration, maybe a few damaged fan blades.\n\nThe engine almost always keeps producing at least 70-90 %% power.\n\nDual-engine failures from bird strikes are one-in-millions rarities:\n\nThe famous \"Miracle on the Hudson\" (US Airways 1549, 2009) was a stunning exception: they hit a whole flock of Canada geese at exactly the wrong altitude (2,800 ft) and lost both engines completely, but glided to a safe ditching with zero fatalities. Tragically, a second such event occurred on December 29, 2024, with Jeju Air Flight 2216 in South Korea - a Boeing 737-800 that ingested a flock of large migratory ducks (Baikal teals) into both engines during approach, leading to dual failure, a belly landing, runway excursion, and 179 fatalities out of 181 aboard. These are the only two confirmed cases in commercial jet history of simultaneous multiple large bird ingestion causing total dual-engine flameout. Every other dual-engine failure on record has been from volcanic ash, fuel issues, or other non-bird causes.\n\nIf one engine is badly damaged during takeoff:\n\nThe plane climbs away on the remaining engine (they are certified to do this even on the hottest day with full passengers). The pilots shut the damaged engine down, fly a big circuit, and land 10-20 minutes later. Passengers usually don\'t even realise how serious it was until they read the news the next day.\n\nAirports actively chase birds away:\nAir-horns, pyrotechnics, falcons, dogs, radar systems, grass management - they spend millions doing it.\nTakeoffs and landings are timed to avoid peak bird activity when possible.\nIf a big flock is near the runway, they delay the departure until it’s clear.\n\nBottom line: if you hear a loud bang or see feathers on takeoff, remind yourself:\n\n\"Engines eat birds for breakfast. This plane was literally designed and tested for this exact moment.\"\n\nYou\'ll be on the ground again in 15 minutes, drinking coffee and reading the headline about how routine it was.</string>

    <string name="learn_section_flight">During the Flight</string>

    <string name="flight_q1">What if we run out of fuel over the ocean?</string>
    <string name="flight_a1">Short answer: Fuel exhaustion has happened a handful of times on scheduled passenger jets, but none have ever ended in a fatal crash or ditching—every case resulted in a safe landing (though some were emergency glides). The key is that aviation learns from each one, and procedures have gotten dramatically better since those early incidents, making repeats extremely unlikely today.\n\nHere\'s the straight facts on why it\'s not the nightmare you\'re imagining:\n\nThe legal fuel rules are a huge safety net\n\nEvery flight must carry:\nFuel to the destination\nFuel to a chosen alternate airport (often 1,000+ miles away)\nAn extra 45 minutes of flying after reaching the alternate\nPlus whatever extra the captain decides to add\n\nThat means the plane could fly to its destination, miss it, fly to another continent, and still circle for nearly an hour before the tanks are legally empty.\n\nIn real life, you carry way more\n\nA typical transatlantic flight takes off with 3-5 hours of extra fuel beyond the plan. That\'s why you almost always land with 8-20 tons still sloshing in the tanks - enough for another entire flight to Europe.\n\nChecks catch problems early\n\nFuel is loaded by ground staff, double-checked by the pilots on paper and on cockpit screens, and monitored second-by-second by the aircraft computers. If burn rate is even slightly higher than expected (headwinds, etc.), alarms sound and the pilots divert while they still have hours of fuel left.\n\nOcean routes are planned with backups everywhere\n\nUnder ETOPS/EDTO rules, every point on the route is within 180-370 minutes of a suitable airport (even on one engine). That\'s why you fly near Iceland, Greenland, the Azores, Goose Bay, Gander, etc. - there are always runways within reach.\n\nThe real incidents? They all ended safely—and fixed the system\n\nSince commercial jets started flying passengers in the late 1950s, there have been rare fuel exhaustion events on scheduled passenger flights, but zero fatalities from them. Here\'s what happened in the big ones:\n\nGimli Glider (Air Canada 143, 1983): A metric/imperial unit mix-up (pounds vs. kilograms) plus a faulty fuel gauge led to half the needed fuel. Both engines quit at 41,000 feet over Canada. The pilots glided 65 miles to an emergency landing at a disused airstrip (now a racetrack)—it was a rough touchdown with minor injuries from evacuation, but no serious harm or deaths to the 69 on board. Aftermath: Air Canada revamped fuel-loading checklists, added mandatory cross-checks for units, improved crew training on the new metric system, and upgraded fuel indication systems to prevent gauge failures. These changes became industry standards, slashing similar errors.\n\nAir Transat 236 (2001): A cracked fuel line from poor maintenance caused a massive leak over the Atlantic. The plane lost all fuel and glided 75 miles to Lajes Air Base in the Azores—tires burst on landing due to no power for brakes, but everyone (306 people) walked away unhurt. Aftermath: Led to global mandates for better post-maintenance leak checks, enhanced fuel imbalance monitoring (pilots now act faster on warnings), and stricter inspections of fuel lines. Airlines like Air Transat faced fines and overhauled procedures, making undetected leaks rare.\n\nOther cases (like Avianca 052 in 1990) involved fuel mismanagement during delays, but even those—73 deaths—spurred huge fixes like better pilot-ATC communication rules and low-fuel declaration protocols. No repeats at that scale.\n\nBottom line: These weren\'t \"safe landings\" by luck alone—the huge fuel buffers, glide training, and quick crew decisions made the difference. And every one triggered fixes that make it harder for errors to snowball today: automated alerts, redundant sensors, and zero-tolerance maintenance. You\'re on a plane with 60+ years of those lessons baked in.\n\nYou\'re carrying more spare fuel right now than most cars have in their tank for an entire road trip.\n\nRunning out and crashing? That\'s not how it works anymore. Breathe easy—the system\'s evolved to keep you safe.</string>

    <string name="flight_q2">Why does the plane keep suddenly dropping or jumping 50-100 ft? (Clear-air turbulence)</string>
    <string name="flight_a2">That stomach-in-your-throat drop feels like the plane just fell out of the sky, but it didn\'t. You dropped maybe 10-30 metres at most, and the plane was never in danger.\n\nHere\'s exactly what\'s happening:\n\nIt\'s clear-air turbulence (CAT)\n\nHigh-altitude wind currents (jet streams) can have invisible \"waves\" or shear lines. The air suddenly speeds up or slows down by 20-50 knots in a thin layer. When the plane crosses that boundary, it feels like hitting an air pocket - exactly like a speed bump in a car.\n\nThe plane is designed for it\n\nCommercial jets are certified to handle gusts up to +50 ft/sec (over 3,000 ft/min vertical speed) without structural damage. A typical CAT encounter is only 10-20 ft/sec - well inside the safety margin. The wings flex on purpose to absorb it.\n\nThose big drops you feel?\n\nThe aircraft might lose 50-150 ft of altitude for 2-4 seconds, then climb right back. The altimeter barely moves - your body just exaggerates it because there\'s no visual reference at 35,000 ft.\n\nPilots see it coming (most of the time)\n\nWeather radars, satellite reports, and reports from planes ahead (PIREPs) give warning minutes in advance. That\'s why the seat-belt sign suddenly comes on \"out of nowhere.\" When it\'s truly unexpected, pilots slow to the official turbulence speed (usually 270-280 knots) to reduce the jolt.\n\nZero crashes from CAT in modern jets\n\nSince the 1960s, not a single commercial passenger jet has ever broken up or crashed because of clear-air turbulence - even in the worst recorded cases (like BOAC Flight 911 in 1966, which was pre-modern wing design and extreme mountain-wave conditions). Today\'s planes and forecasting make that impossible.\n\nNext time you feel that sudden drop, remind yourself:\n\n\"It\'s just the air version of a pothole. The plane shrugged it off and we\'re already back to smooth air.\"\n\nIt always passes in seconds. Keep your seat-belt loosely fastened and you\'re golden.</string>

    <string name="flight_q3">The engines just got quieter - did they reduce power too much or turn one off?</string>
    <string name="flight_a3">No, they didn\'t turn anything off and they didn\'t cut power too much. The sudden drop in engine noise is 100 %% normal and deliberate.\n\nHere\'s exactly what you just heard:\n\nCruise-climb or step-climb power reduction\n\nRight after levelling off or after a step-climb to a higher altitude, the autopilot switches from \"take-off/climb thrust\" (loud) to \"cruise thrust\" (much quieter). It happens automatically and can cut the engine noise by 30-50 %% in a few seconds. It feels dramatic because the cabin was already quiet after takeoff.\n\nCost-index / economy cruise setting\n\nAirlines programme the plane to fly at the most fuel-efficient power setting once at cruising altitude. That means the engines idle back to around 85-92 %% N1 (fan speed) instead of the 100-105 %% they used for climb. Perfectly safe - the engines are designed to run like this for 12+ hours.\n\nYou\'re now in the thinner air at 35,000-39,000 ft\n\nThe higher you go, the less air there is for the engines to \"scream\" against. Same thrust, way less noise inside the cabin.\n\nIf one engine actually was shut down (extremely rare)\n\nYou would hear a loud yaw (the plane slews sideways), the cabin lights would flicker, and the pilots would announce it within seconds. A quiet engine change without any of that = normal cruise mode.\n\nReal-world proof: every long-haul flight you\'ve ever been on did this exact thing 10-30 minutes after takeoff.\n\nThe engines are now purring efficiently instead of roaring - exactly what they\'re supposed to do for the next 8-12 hours. Nothing is wrong. In fact, everything is going exactly right.\n\nEnjoy the quiet - it means you\'re safely in cruise.</string>

    <string name="flight_q4">What if both engines fail at the same time up here?</string>
    <string name="flight_a4">Short answer: It\'s extremely rare - fewer than 20 documented cases in commercial passenger jets since 1960 - but when it has happened, pilots have always been able to glide the plane safely to a landing. No one has ever died from a mid-flight dual engine failure where the crew had time to respond (the tragedies were from low-altitude events or other factors).\n\nHere\'s the straight reality:\n\nWhat causes it? Always something shared or external\n\nEngines are built separately, so they don\'t fail together randomly. The triggers are:\nFuel issues (exhaustion or contamination - like the Gimli Glider or Air Transat 236, both safe glides).\n\nBird flocks (US Airways 1549 Hudson ditching, 0 deaths; Jeju Air 2216 2024 crash, but during approach, not cruise).\n\nVolcanic ash (British Airways 9, 1982 - all engines quit, restarted mid-air, safe landing).\n\nIcing or hail (SAS 751, 1991 - both engines iced, safe emergency landing).\n\nPilots get warnings minutes or hours ahead for most of these.\n\nThe plane turns into a glider - and it\'s good at it\n\nFrom 35,000 ft, a twin-jet like a 737 glides 100+ miles (20-30 minutes). A widebody like a 777 goes 150-180 miles. That\'s plenty of time to reach an airport or field. The autopilot and controls keep working via backup power (ram air turbine pops out automatically).\n\nPilots train for this constantly\n\nEvery six months in the simulator, they practice dual failure at the worst spot - engines out, glide to landing. It\'s routine, not panic. Real cases:\nAir Transat 236 (2001): Fuel leak over Atlantic, glided 75 miles to Azores - 306 safe.\n\nBritish Airways 38 (2008): Fuel icing on approach, crash-landed short of runway - minor injuries only.\n\nPinnacle 3701 (2004): Both engines failed at 41,000 ft from high-altitude stall; crashed during restart attempts - both pilots died, but it was a ferry flight (no passengers) and led to better high-altitude training.\n\nThe numbers: Rare, and survivable\n\nOut of billions of flight hours since 1960, dual failures in passenger jets number under 20 (mostly safe). Single engine failure? 1 in 375,000 hours. Dual? 1 in billions. Jets are certified to fly and land on one engine anyway, so losing both is the ultimate test - and they\'ve passed every time with time on their side.\n\nIf it happens up here, you\'d hear announcements, feel a yaw, and the plane would start a controlled descent. The crew\'s got 20+ minutes and a checklist for it.\n\nYou\'re safer from dual failure than from a car breakdown on the highway. Buckle up, but relax - the plane\'s built for this.</string>

    <string name="flight_q5">We\'re flying over the ocean/mountains with no airport for hours - what if something goes wrong?</string>
    <string name="flight_a5">That empty expanse below feels terrifying, but you\'re actually surrounded by more runways than you think, and the plane is built exactly for this scenario.\n\nHere\'s the real picture:\n\nYou\'re never truly \"nowhere\"\n\nOn every long over-water or remote route, the flight plan is drawn so that at any moment—even on one engine—you are within 180-370 minutes of a suitable airport (ETOPS/EDTO rules). That means places like:\nIceland, Greenland, the Azores, Canary Islands\nGoose Bay, Gander, Iqaluit (Canada)\nShemya, Anchorage (Alaska)\nHawaii, Fiji, Tahiti in the Pacific\n\nThese are pre-approved emergency airfields with long runways, fire trucks, and medical teams on standby 24/7.\n\nThe plane is certified to fly hours on one engine\n\nYour aircraft (737, A320, 777, A350, etc.) has been tested and proven to fly, climb, and cruise for 3-6+ hours with one engine completely shut down. Losing one engine doesn\'t mean you\'re falling—it just means a slower cruise and a diversion to one of those fields.\n\nIf both engines quit (the absolute nightmare)\n\nYou still glide 100-180 miles from cruising altitude (20-30 minutes). That\'s enough to reach land or a ship in almost every case. Real examples (Air Transat 236, US Airways 1549) both reached safe landing spots from the middle of nowhere.\n\nConstant tracking and instant help\n\nADS-B and satellite coverage mean ATC and the airline know your exact position every second.\n\nIf anything goes wrong, military jets can be scrambled, ships redirected, and the closest runway cleared in minutes.\n\nMany remote airfields (e.g., Lajes in the Azores, Keflavik in Iceland) exist mainly for transatlantic emergencies—they get a few diversions every year and handle them perfectly.\n\nReal-life proof\n\nEvery year a handful of flights divert to these \"middle-of-nowhere\" bases for medical issues, technical problems, or weather. Passengers get off, have coffee, and continue the next day. Zero drama.\n\nSo when you look out and see nothing but water or mountains, remember: the route was drawn around invisible safety islands, and the plane can reach one of them even in the worst case.\n\nYou\'re not flying over emptiness—you\'re flying a carefully planned highway in the sky with emergency exits every 1,000 miles.</string>

    <string name="flight_q6">What if the cabin suddenly depressurises? (oxygen masks drop)</string>
    <string name="flight_a6">It feels like the worst-case scenario, but it\'s one of the best-practised and safest emergencies in aviation.\n\nHere\'s exactly what happens and why you\'re okay:\n\nThe masks drop automatically\n\nThe second cabin pressure drops too low (around 10,000-14,000 ft equivalent), the masks fall out on their own. No one has to do anything. You have 12-20 minutes of oxygen from the moment you pull one down - far more than you\'ll ever need.\n\nYou have plenty of time to breathe\n\nFrom cruising altitude the pilots immediately start an emergency descent to 10,000 ft (where you can breathe normally). That takes only 2-4 minutes. You\'ll be back in normal air long before the mask supply gets low.\n\nThe plane is built for big holes\n\nThe fuselage is tested to fly and land safely even with a hole the size of a door or larger. The structure stays intact, the wings keep producing lift, and the controls keep working.\n\nWhat you\'ll feel and hear\n\nLoud rush of air and cold\nFog in the cabin (moisture condensing)\nThe plane banks and dives steeply (this is deliberate and fast - the correct way to get you oxygen)\nPilots will announce \"Masks on, emergency descent\" or similar\n\nWhat to do - three simple steps\n\nGrab the nearest mask and pull it sharply toward you (oxygen starts instantly)\nPut your own mask on first (yes, even before kids - you stay conscious to help them)\nTighten the straps and breathe normally\n\nThat\'s it.\n\nThe masks dropping is the system working perfectly.\n\nIn 2-4 minutes you\'ll level off at a safe altitude, the cold and noise will ease, and the plane will divert to the nearest airport for a normal landing. Hypoxia (lack of oxygen) has never killed a passenger in a depressurisation when the masks deployed and people used them.\n\nIt\'s loud and scary, but it\'s a solved problem. You\'ll be fine.</string>

    <string name="flight_q7">What if there is a fire on board?</string>
    <string name="flight_a7">Fire on a passenger jet is taken so seriously that the plane is literally built to detect it instantly and kill it before it can spread.\n\nHere\'s exactly how it works:\n\nDetection is automatic and everywhere\n\nSmoke and heat sensors cover every cargo hold, lavatory, cockpit, avionics bay, and cabin ceiling. The first trace triggers loud alarms in the cockpit within seconds.\n\nSuppression is immediate\nCargo holds: pilots press one button -> built-in bottles flood the hold with fire-extinguishing gas (Halon or equivalent). It starves the fire of oxygen and keeps it out for the rest of the flight.\n\nCabin/lavatory: flight attendants carry multiple large extinguishers and are trained to empty them into the source in under a minute.\n\nEngines and electronics: automatic fire bottles discharge the moment overheating is detected.\n\nNothing burns easily\n\nSeats, walls, carpets, wiring insulation, and cargo liners are all fire-resistant or fire-proof by law. They are designed to withstand direct flame for minutes without spreading fire.\n\nThe rule is simple: land NOW\n\nThe moment smoke or fire is confirmed, the pilots divert to the nearest suitable airport. Air traffic control clears the way and you\'ll be on the ground in 15-25 minutes on average.\n\nWhat you\'ll experience\nYou might smell a brief burnt odour or see the crew moving fast with extinguishers.\n\nThe captain will announce a diversion (\"we have a technical issue and are landing at the nearest airport\").\n\nThe flight ends early, but safely.\n\nThat\'s it.\n\nThe entire system - detectors, suppressants, materials, and procedures - is designed so a fire never gets the chance to become dangerous.\n\nIf it ever happens, it\'s handled fast, contained, and you walk off the plane at the next airport.</string>

    <string name="flight_q8">What if ice builds up on the wings and we can\'t get it off?</string>
    <string name="flight_a8">Ice on wings is a real concern, but modern commercial jets are equipped with reliable systems to prevent and remove it before it affects flight. While icing has contributed to some accidents in the past (mostly on turboprops or due to human error), the built-in protections make uncontrolled buildup extremely rare.\n\nHere\'s exactly how it works:\n\nAnti-icing runs continuously in cruise\n\nHot air from the engines (bleed air) is automatically routed to heat the leading edges of the wings, tail, and engine inlets. This melts ice as it forms, and the system activates on its own when sensors detect moisture and cold temperatures - often without the pilots doing anything.\n\nDe-icing boots for extra protection (on some models)\n\nIf needed, inflatable rubber strips on the wing and tail edges expand and contract every 1-3 minutes, cracking off any ice buildup. This is standard on many regional jets and works in seconds.\n\nGround procedures eliminate the risk before takeoff\n\nBefore any flight in cold weather, de-icing trucks spray special fluid that removes all frost, snow, or ice and coats the wings to prevent new buildup for 10-60 minutes. Pilots inspect visually or with tools, and no plane leaves the gate unless the wings are spotless.\n\nPilots and tech monitor it 24/7\nCockpit ice detectors trigger lights and alerts if buildup starts.\nAt night, wing inspection lights let the crew check the edges every few minutes.\nWeather radar and forecasts keep the plane out of known icing layers, or they descend to warmer air if needed.\n\nWhat it feels like (and why it\'s safe)\n\nYou might notice a brief vibration or hear the anti-ice pumps whir - that\'s the system doing its job. At cruising speeds (450-550 knots), air friction helps shed ice too. The plane is certified to handle minor buildup without losing lift.\n\nThese systems have made wing icing a non-issue for most commercial jets. If conditions are severe, pilots simply avoid them or divert. Your flight is designed to fly through clouds without a worry - the ice never stands a chance.</string>

    <string name="flight_q9">What if we get hit by lightning?</string>
    <string name="flight_a9">Short answer: It happens to almost every commercial jet once or twice a year, and nothing bad ever happens. The plane is literally a flying lightning rod built to take it.\n\nHere\'s exactly what happens:\n\nThe plane is designed to be struck\n\nThe entire skin is aluminium or carbon composite with metal mesh/foil inside - it conducts electricity perfectly. Lightning enters at one point (usually nose or wingtip), travels around the outside, and exits at another (tail or opposite wingtip). Passengers and systems inside are completely shielded.\n\nYou\'ll feel/hear it\nA bright flash\nA loud bang or crack (like a gunshot right next to you)\nSometimes a brief flicker of cabin lights\n\nThat\'s it. The plane doesn\'t shake, drop, or change course.\n\nAutomatic protection\nAll critical systems (engines, flight controls, avionics) are triple-redundant and shielded.\nSurge protectors absorb any stray current.\nFuel tanks have inerting systems so sparks can\'t ignite fuel.\n\nAfter the strike\n\nPilots get a cockpit message, report it to maintenance, and the plane lands normally. On the ground, engineers do a quick walk-around and check for tiny burn marks (usually just surface scorch). 99 %% of the time the plane flies its next flight the same day.\n\nReal numbers\n\nAverage commercial jet is struck 1-2 times per year.\n\nIn the last 50+ years of jet travel, zero passengers or crew have ever been injured by a lightning strike, and zero planes have crashed or even made an emergency landing because of one.\n\nIf you see a flash and hear a massive bang - that\'s just the plane doing its job as a Faraday cage.\n\nIt\'s loud, it\'s startling, but it\'s completely harmless.\n\nRelax - you just got a free light show.</string>

    <!-- Landing Items -->
    <string name="landing_q1">How Pilots Decide If It’s Safe to Land</string>
    <string name="landing_a1">Imagine you’re sitting at your window seat on final approach. The runway lights are in sight, the seat-belt sign has been on forever, and suddenly… the engines roar, the nose pitches up, and you’re climbing again. Your heart jumps. “Something went wrong!” you think.\n\nActually, the opposite happened: everything just went exactly right.\n\nHere’s what really happens in the cockpit when pilots decide whether to land or “go around.”\n\n1. The Golden Rule: The Stabilised Approach\nEvery airline in the world (and every major regulator: FAA, EASA, ICAO) requires a “stabilised approach.”\n\nThat means by no later than 1,000 feet above the ground in good weather (or 500 feet in bad weather), the aircraft MUST meet every single one of these criteria:\n• Correct speed: not more than +10 knots or –5 knots from target\n• On the correct vertical path (the “glide slope” – the invisible 3-degree highway in the sky)\n• Only small heading changes needed (basically pointing at the runway)\n• Landing checklist and configuration complete: gear down, flaps set\n• Engines spooled up and stable (no big power changes needed)\n• Sink rate not excessive (normally less than 1,000 ft/min, much less near the ground)\n\nIf even one of those things is off — and it can’t be fixed instantly — the pilots are trained, and in many airlines required, to go around.\n\n2. Who Actually Makes the Decision?\nBoth pilots are monitoring. The pilot flying (PF) is hand-flying or watching the autopilot.\n\nThe pilot monitoring (PM) is calling out deviations: “Speed ten high… sinking eight hundred… slightly low on glide path…”\n\nAt many airlines the monitoring pilot literally says out loud at 1,000 ft: “Stabilised” or “Unstabilised – go around.”\n\nIf it’s unstabilised, the default answer is go around. Trying to “save” a bad approach is how almost all runway-overrun accidents start.\n\n3. Common Reasons for a Go-Around (none of them are emergencies)\n• Wind shear or sudden gusts that push the plane off the centreline or speed\n• The aircraft ahead is still on the runway and hasn’t cleared the “protected zone”\n• Unstable approach (too fast, too high, wrong flap setting, etc.)\n• Glideslope or localiser signal momentarily drops out in bad weather\n• Runway surface suddenly reported as contaminated (standing water, heavy braking action reports)\n• Deer or birds on the runway (yes, really)\n• ATC says “Go around” because of spacing or traffic conflict\n\nOnly about 1–3 flights in every 1,000 actually go around, but when they do, it’s celebrated in the industry. EasyJet, Ryanair, Delta, Emirates – they all have “Go-Around of the Month” awards. Seriously.\n\n4. What Happens When They Go Around\n• The pilot flying pushes the TOGA buttons (Take-Off/Go-Around) on the thrust levers\n• Full (or nearly full) power is applied automatically\n• The autopilot (if engaged) pitches the nose up to the perfect climb angle\n• Flaps are retracted one stage for better climb performance\n• Gear comes up\n• The plane follows a published “missed approach procedure” – a pre-programmed escape route that keeps you clear of mountains and other traffic\n\nYou feel exactly like a normal take-off, because that’s basically what it is: a take-off from 50–200 feet in the air.\n\n5. After the Go-Around\nYou’ll usually fly a quick circuit or a slightly longer loop, clean the aircraft up, and try again 5–15 minutes later when everything is perfect.\n\nIn worse weather you might hold for 20–30 minutes while the storm passes, or divert to your alternate airport (which was planned before you even left the gate).\n\n6. The Safety Statistics Are Insane\nModern go-around rates have helped make commercial flying ridiculously safe.\n\nIn the last 15 years there has been exactly ONE passenger fatality in a scheduled jet landing accident in the United States (Asiana 214 in 2013 – and that happened precisely because the crew ignored an unstable approach and did NOT go around).\n\nWorldwide, your chance of being in a fatal landing accident is roughly 1 in 20–30 million flights.\n\nSo when you feel that surge of power and the plane climbs away, smile.\n\nTwo highly trained pilots, backed by decades of engineering and strict procedures, just chose the safest possible option.\n\nA go-around isn’t a near-miss.\nIt’s the system working perfectly.\nYou’re not “almost in trouble.”\nYou’re in the safest place you could possibly be.</string>

    <string name="landing_q2">Why the Wings Flex and Wobble on Landing</string>
    <string name="landing_a2">If you’re sitting by the window and can see the wing, you’ve probably noticed how much it moves. It bends upward in flight, then ripples and flexes the moment the wheels touch the runway. Those smooth, flowing motions are completely normal — and they’re one of the smartest safety features on the plane.\n\nHere’s why it happens and why it keeps you safer.\n\n1. Wings are built to flex — on purpose\nA Boeing 787’s wingtips can move upward more than 8 metres (26 feet) in flight.\nAn Airbus A350 can flex nearly 9 metres at the tips.\nEvery modern jet is designed this way, whether the wings are aluminium or carbon fibre.\n\nEngineers make the wings flexible so they can absorb huge forces instead of fighting them. A stiff wing would transfer every bump and gust straight to the cabin. A flexible wing soaks up the energy like a shock absorber.\n\n2. What’s happening at touchdown\nWhile you’re descending, the wings are bent upward because they’re producing lift. The moment the wheels touch:\n• Lift disappears in a split second.\n• All the aircraft’s weight shifts to the landing gear.\n• The wings gently spring back toward their natural shape.\n\nThat smooth “unloading” is what creates the graceful ripple you see. Any leftover energy makes the wing oscillate a couple of times — just like a diving board settling after someone jumps off.\n\n3. Windy landings make the movement even more noticeable\nIn gusty or crosswind conditions the wings are constantly adjusting right until touchdown. When the plane finally settles on the runway, all that stored energy is released at once, so the flexing looks more dramatic. The more the wing moves, the more energy it just absorbed for you.\n\n4. Real-world testing proves how strong they are\nBefore any new aircraft flies passengers, the wings are tested to extremes:\n• The plane is bolted to the ground.\n• Hydraulic rams bend the wings far beyond anything they’ll ever experience in service — usually 150% of the maximum load they’ll ever see.\n• The wings have to hold that position for several seconds and then return perfectly to shape.\n\nThe 787’s wings were flexed almost 8 metres upward in public testing — and sprang back as if nothing happened.\n\n5. Carbon-fibre wings (787, A350, 777X) take it even further\nNewer wings made of composite materials actually like to flex. They don’t develop tiny cracks over time the way metal can, and they stay smooth and strong for decades.\n\nThe calm bottom line\nThat gentle bending and rippling isn’t a sign of stress — it’s the wing doing its job exactly as designed. Every movement you see is energy that never reaches you.\n\nNext time you watch the wing flow and flex after landing, you can relax and think:\n“Everything is working perfectly. Those wings just turned a firm arrival into a smooth one.”\n\nYou’re witnessing brilliant engineering in action — and it’s keeping your ride as comfortable and safe as possible.</string>

    <string name="landing_q3">Braking Systems Explained: Reverse Thrust, Autobrake, and Anti-Skid</string>
    <string name="landing_a3">The moment the wheels touch down, a whole orchestra of braking systems kicks in automatically. You feel a gentle push forward in your seat, you hear a roar from the engines, and the plane slows down smoothly and predictably. Nothing is left to chance – everything is designed, tested, and triple-redundant.\n\nHere’s exactly what’s happening and why you can completely relax.\n\n1. Reverse Thrust – the loud roar that does most of the slowing at first\nAs soon as the main wheels touch the runway, big doors (or sleeves) on the engines flip forward.\nThe engines still produce the same power, but now most of the air is blown forward instead of backward.\nIt’s like opening a parachute behind a speeding car – you feel yourself pressed gently into the seat belt.\n\nModern engines are incredibly clever:\n• On Airbus aircraft, reverse thrust engages automatically the moment weight is on the wheels.\n• On Boeing, the pilot lifts the reverse levers, but the plane won’t let them deploy in the air – a safety lock prevents it.\n• Usually only about 50–70% reverse power is used on dry runways (to save brakes and engines). In rain or on short runways, they can use full reverse.\n\nYou’ll hear the roar fade away after 10–15 seconds because the plane is already slowing nicely.\n\n2. Autobrake – the invisible co-pilot who does the braking for you\nBefore landing, the pilots turn a knob to select one of five settings:\n• 1 or 2: gentle braking for long runways (you barely feel it)\n• 3: medium, most common on normal runways\n• MAX/AUTO MAX: very firm, used on short or slippery runways\n\nThe moment the wheels spin up (proving you’re really on the ground), the autobrake applies exactly the right pressure to slow the plane at a steady, pre-chosen rate.\nIt’s smoother and more consistent than even the best human pilot could manage, and it works together with anti-skid (see below).\nIf the pilots want to stop sooner, they simply press the brake pedals – autobrake instantly hands over control and disengages.\n\n3. Anti-Skid – the system that makes skidding almost impossible\nEvery main wheel has its own speed sensor. A computer watches all of them 20–40 times per second.\nIf one wheel starts slowing down much faster than the others (about to lock up on a wet or icy patch), the computer instantly releases that brake for a fraction of a second, then re-applies it – many times faster than a Formula 1 driver could.\n\nYou might feel a very slight pulsing or rumbling through the floor on a wet runway – that’s anti-skid doing its job perfectly. It guarantees the plane stops in a straight line and uses every bit of available grip.\n\n4. Extra layers of safety you never notice\n• Even if all wheel brakes failed completely, reverse thrust alone can stop most jets on a normal runway.\n• If reverse thrust failed, the wheel brakes and anti-skid can easily stop the plane.\n• If both failed (almost unheard of), the runway still has thousands of metres of overrun area, and many have engineered material (EMAS) – a special crushable concrete that stops a plane gently.\n\n5. Real numbers that calm the mind\nA Boeing 737 landing at 140 knots (260 km/h) on a dry runway with autobrake 3 stops in about 35–40 seconds and uses roughly 1,600–1,800 metres.\nOn a soaking wet runway it might need 2,200–2,400 metres – and every major airport runway is at least that long (most are 3,000–4,000 m).\nThe pilots already calculated the exact distance needed before takeoff, and the runway has huge safety margins built in.\n\nSo when you feel that gentle push forward, hear the engines roar, and watch the runway lights slow down outside your window – everything is working exactly as it should.\nThree independent, computer-controlled systems are sharing the job, watching each other, and making sure you stop smoothly and safely every single time.\n\nYou’re not relying on luck or a pilot stomping on the brakes.\nYou’re being slowed by some of the most reliable technology ever built.</string>

    <string name="landing_q4">Landing in Heavy Rain – How Pilots See the Runway</string>
    <string name="landing_a4">When you look outside and see torrential rain streaking across the window, it’s easy to wonder how the pilots can possibly see anything. The truth is: they don’t need to see nearly as much as you think, and everything is built to work perfectly even when the windshield looks like a car wash.\n\nHere’s exactly how it works.\n\n1. The runway is lit up like a Christmas tree\nModern runway edge lights, centreline lights, and approach lights are incredibly bright and designed to cut through heavy rain:\n• They are visible from 5–8 km (3–5 miles) away even in a downpour.\n• They are spaced every 30–60 metres and colour-coded (white → amber → red) so pilots instantly know how far they are from the end.\n• Touchdown zone lights and high-intensity strobes guide the last few seconds.\n\n2. Windshield wipers that actually work\nAirliner wipers are nothing like your car’s:\n• They sweep 2–3 times per second (faster than any road vehicle).\n• They are powered by hydraulic systems, not little electric motors.\n• Many aircraft have a hydrophobic rain-repellent coating (like Rain-X on steroids) that makes water bead and fly off instantly.\n• If it’s really torrential, the pilot can switch on a second layer of clear liquid repellent that spreads across the windshield.\n\n3. The invisible highway in the sky: ILS and beyond\nThe Instrument Landing System (ILS) is two radio beams:\n• One tells the plane if it’s left or right of the centreline (the “localiser”).\n• One tells it if it’s too high or too low (the “glideslope”).\n\nThese beams are accurate to within a few metres and work perfectly in any weather. On most flights, the autopilot follows them all the way down to 200 ft or lower. In really bad rain, the pilots can couple the autoland system and the plane flies itself to touchdown.\n\n4. Head-Up Display (HUD) – like a video game for pilots\nMany modern cockpits (especially Boeings) have a transparent screen right in the pilot’s line of sight:\n• A glowing green ladder and runway outline is projected onto the windshield.\n• Even if the real runway is barely visible through rain, the pilot sees a perfect virtual runway floating in front of them.\n• The HUD is so good that pilots can hand-fly a perfect approach in conditions where the windshield is almost opaque.\n\n5. Wet runway performance – calculated to the metre\nBefore every flight, the crew receives a detailed weather package. For rain they get:\n• Exact braking action reports from planes that landed minutes earlier (“braking action good/medium/poor”).\n• Precise water depth measurements if there’s standing water.\n\nThey plug those numbers into an iPad or EFB (Electronic Flight Bag). The software tells them the exact runway distance needed – with huge safety margins. If the numbers don’t add up, they divert long before they even start the approach. No guessing.\n\n6. Grooved runways and special tyres\nAlmost every major airport runway has thousands of tiny grooves cut into the surface (like the tread on a tyre). Water drains away instantly, so there’s almost never a sheet of water to hydroplane on.\nAircraft tyres have deep grooves and are inflated to 200+ psi – they squeeze water out sideways like a squeegee.\n\n7. The calm reality\nHydroplaning accidents on commercial jets are virtually unheard of in the last 30 years.\nIn the very rare event visibility drops below limits while on approach, the plane simply goes around automatically – exactly like in clear weather.\n\nSo when the rain is pouring down and the wipers are going like crazy, the pilots are relaxed.\nThey’re following bright lights and precise radio beams, the runway is draining perfectly, and multiple computers are double-checking everything.\n\nYou’re not landing “through” a storm.\nYou’re following a perfectly engineered path that works the same in sunshine or monsoon.</string>

    <string name="landing_q5">Crosswind Landings: Why the Plane Flies Sideways</string>
    <string name="landing_a5">When the wind is blowing across the runway instead of straight down it, the approach and touchdown can look dramatic from your window. The plane might fly in at an angle, the nose pointed off to one side, and at the last second it straightens up. It looks wild, but it’s one of the most practiced and safest maneuvers pilots do every day.\n\nHere’s exactly what’s happening and why it’s completely under control.\n\n1. Two techniques pilots use (often together)\n• The Crab: High up on final approach, the pilot points the nose into the wind. The plane is flying sideways through the air, but the track over the ground stays perfectly lined up with the runway. From your seat it looks like the plane is drifting sideways; it’s not. It’s moving straight down the runway centerline.\n\n• The Wing-Low (or sideslip): As the plane gets lower, the pilot lowers one wing into the wind and uses opposite rudder to keep the nose pointed straight down the runway. This is the smooth ballet move you sometimes see.\n\nMost landings use a bit of both: crab on the way down, then transition to wing-low in the last 100–200 feet.\n\n2. The “kick-out” or de-crab at the end\nJust before the wheels touch, the pilot straightens the nose with rudder and levels the wings (or almost levels them).\nThat quick rudder movement is what makes the plane suddenly line up with the runway. It feels like a gentle bump or sway, nothing more.\nThe whole thing happens in 1–2 seconds and is practiced hundreds of times in the simulator.\n\n3. The landing gear is built for sideways loads\nThe main wheels and gear legs are deliberately designed to handle big side loads.\nThey can touch down with the plane drifting slightly sideways and absorb it without stress. On some aircraft (especially Boeing), the gear even tilts slightly on touchdown to make it smoother.\n\n4. Real crosswind limits (what the plane can actually handle)\nTypical maximum demonstrated crosswind components for common jets:\n• Boeing 737: 35–38 knots\n• Airbus A320 family: 38 knots\n• Boeing 777: 40–44 knots\n• Boeing 787 &amp; Airbus A350: 40–44 knots\n\nAirlines usually set their own limit 5–10 knots lower than that for extra comfort and safety.\nA 25–30 knot crosswind feels noticeable to passengers but is routine for crews; they land in it several times a week.\n\n5. How pilots train for it\nEvery six months pilots spend hours in the simulator practicing crosswind landings in 40-knot gusting winds, low visibility, wet runways, and even engine failures combined with crosswinds.\nThey have to prove they can land safely in the worst conditions the airline allows before they’re allowed to fly passengers.\n\n6. The calm truth\nThat sideways approach and last-second straightening isn’t the pilot “fighting” the wind.\nIt’s a deliberate, carefully taught technique that has been perfected over decades.\nThe plane is designed for it, the gear is designed for it, and the pilots have practiced it hundreds of times.\nWhat looks dramatic from row 23 is completely standard from the cockpit.\n\nNext time you see the plane flying in at an angle, you can relax and think:\n“Perfectly normal. They do this all the time, and they’re really good at it.”</string>

    <string name="landing_q6">Fog and Low-Visibility Landings: How the Plane Lands When the Runway Is Invisible</string>
    <string name="landing_a6">When fog, heavy rain, or darkness swallows the runway, the aircraft switches to its most precise and safest mode: autoland. The plane follows two invisible radio beams broadcast from the runway (one for left/right guidance, one for height) that are accurate down to a few centimetres. These beams work perfectly no matter how thick the fog is.\n\nLong before you reach the airport, the crew checks the reported visibility. Most big airports today are equipped for Category III approaches, which means the plane can land with almost zero forward visibility (sometimes as little as 50 metres, sometimes none at all).\n\nHere’s what happens:\n\n1. Two or three independent autopilots are engaged at the same time. They constantly cross-check each other; if they disagree by even a tiny amount, the system instantly disconnects and the plane climbs away automatically for another try.\n\n2. The autopilots fly the entire approach, flare, and touchdown. The flare (that gentle nose-up movement just before the wheels touch) happens at about 50 feet, and the landing is usually smoother than on a clear day because the computers react faster and more precisely than any human can.\n\n3. After the wheels touch, the autobrakes and automatic rudder keep the plane exactly on the centreline until it’s slow enough for the pilots to take over and taxi (many airports now have “follow-the-greens” taxiway lights that guide them through the fog).\n\nEverything is triple-redundant: radios, computers, hydraulics, electrical power. The system is designed so that even if one part fails, the landing continues safely.\n\nPilots train for this every six months in the simulator, and the technology has been in daily use for over fifty years with an impeccable safety record.\n\nSo when the world outside your window turns completely grey or white, nothing is wrong. The aircraft is now being flown with more precision, more redundancy, and less human input than on a bright sunny day.\n\nThe plane doesn’t need to see the runway.\nIt knows exactly where it is, and it’s taking you down perfectly.</string>

    <string name="landing_q7">Landing on Wet or Contaminated Runways: Why the Plane Still Stops</string>
    <string name="landing_a7">Rain, standing water, slush, or even a light dusting of snow doesn’t turn a runway into an ice rink. Everything is measured, calculated, and backed by huge safety margins long before the wheels touch down.\n\nHere’s how it really works.\n\n1. Every time a plane lands ahead of you, the pilots send a short report: “braking action good”, “medium”, or “poor”. Those reports go instantly to every crew waiting to land, including yours.\n\n2. Your pilots take those numbers (plus temperature, wind, and exact water/snow depth if reported) and enter them into an iPad or onboard laptop. In seconds the software tells them exactly how much runway they will need to stop, always with at least a 15–67 % extra safety margin required by law (67 % extra if the braking report is “poor”).\n\nExample: a Boeing 737 on a perfectly dry 3,000-metre runway normally stops in about 1,500–1,800 metres. On a soaking wet runway with “medium” braking it might need 2,400 metres. Every major airport runway is at least 2,500–4,000 metres long, so there is still plenty left over.\n\nIf the numbers are even slightly too close, the pilots simply divert to another airport. They make that decision while still 200–300 miles out, not at the last second.\n\n3. The runway itself helps enormously. Almost all big airports have grooved or porous surfaces that drain water away instantly. A heavy rainstorm can dump buckets, yet within seconds the surface is almost dry again.\n\n4. The tyres are high-pressure (200+ psi) and have deep grooves that squeeze water sideways like a squeegee. Combined with anti-skid brakes that pulse 20–40 times per second, hydroplaning is practically impossible at normal landing speeds.\n\n5. In winter, runways are treated with de-icing liquids and swept constantly. If there’s more than a thin layer of slush or snow, the airport closes the runway until it’s cleared. Airlines won’t land until it’s officially safe.\n\nEven in the extremely rare worst-case where every brake failed (which has never happened on a modern jet), reverse thrust alone can stop the plane, and beyond the end of the runway there are usually 300–1,000 metres of clear safety area, plus crushable concrete beds (EMAS) at many airports that stop a plane gently if it ever overruns.\n\nSo when the runway outside looks shiny and wet, nothing is being left to chance.\nThe distance has already been calculated to the metre, the surface is engineered to drain instantly, and multiple independent braking systems are ready.\n\nThe plane will slow down and stop exactly where it always does, smoothly and predictably.</string>

    <string name="landing_q8">Thunderstorm Avoidance: Why Pilots Never Land in an Active Storm</string>
    <string name="landing_a8">Thunderstorms look dramatic from the ground, but from the cockpit they are treated with absolute respect. No commercial pilot will ever try to land in or near an active storm cell. Here’s why, and how easily it’s avoided.\n\n1. Pilots can see thunderstorms long before you can\nEvery airliner has a weather radar that paints storms in bright red and magenta up to 320 nautical miles (600 km) ahead. A single active cell stands out like a neon sign. Dispatchers on the ground also send updated radar pictures every few minutes.\n\n2. The unbreakable rule: stay at least 20 nautical miles away\nRegulations and airline policy require crews to stay 20 miles (37 km) sideways from any active thunderstorm (more if it’s particularly intense). Above the storm, the distance increases to 5,000–10,000 ft vertically.\nThat distance is so large that lightning, hail, and severe turbulence almost never reach the aircraft.\n\n3. Microbursts and wind shear are the real danger, and they’re detected instantly\nModern aircraft have predictive wind-shear systems that look 3–5 miles ahead. If the air suddenly changes direction or speed (a microburst), the cockpit speakers shout “WINDSHEAR! WINDSHEAR!” and the plane automatically applies full power and climbs.\nThese systems have prevented every single microburst accident since they became standard in the 1990s.\n\n4. If a storm is sitting over the airport\n• Flights hold in large racetrack patterns 50–100 miles away until the cell moves off (usually 20–40 minutes).\n• Or they divert to a planned alternate airport that was chosen before takeoff, with enough extra fuel for exactly this situation.\n• ATC clears entire corridors so no one has to fly near the storm.\n\n5. Lightning is loud but harmless\nAircraft are hit by lightning once or twice a year on average. The aluminium or carbon-fibre skin acts like a Faraday cage; the charge travels around the outside and exits through static wicks on the trailing edges. Passengers and systems inside are completely protected. The pre-flight walk-around checks for tiny entry/exit marks, and that’s it.\n\nThe calm reality\nYou will never see a pilot attempt to “thread the needle” between storm cells to land. If the radar shows red anywhere near the final approach path, the crew simply goes somewhere else.\n\nHolding a little longer or landing at the next suitable airport is so routine that crews treat it like a minor schedule change, not a drama.\n\nSo when you hear the captain say “we’re just going to hold for a few minutes while a storm cell clears the area” or “we’ll be diverting to our alternate,” smile.\nIt means the system is working exactly as it should, keeping you far away from the one type of weather aviation always treats with zero tolerance.</string>

    <string name="landing_q9">Can We Hit a Building or Mountain When Flying in Clouds or Fog?</string>
    <string name="landing_a9">Short answer: No. Not even close.\n\nHere’s why it’s actually impossible on a commercial flight.\n\n1. The plane always knows exactly where it is\nModern airliners use triple GPS + inertial navigation systems that are accurate to within a few metres, even if every satellite disappeared.\nThese systems never drift more than a couple of hundred metres even after flying across the Atlantic with zero outside references.\n\n2. The ground is mapped in 3D\nEvery aircraft carries an Enhanced Ground-Proximity Warning System (EGPWS) with a worldwide terrain and obstacle database.\nIt knows the height and exact location of every mountain, radio tower, and tall building on Earth.\nIf the plane ever gets within about 30 seconds of hitting anything, the cockpit blares “TERRAIN! TERRAIN! PULL UP!” and a big red warning flashes. The system has saved hundreds of flights.\n\n3. Air traffic control has multiple safety nets\n• Controllers see your exact position and altitude on radar.\n• Their Minimum Safe Altitude Warning (MSAW) system automatically alerts them if you descend below a safe height for your location.\n• In busy areas, TCAS (the anti-collision system) will tell you to climb or descend if you ever get near high ground, even if everyone else somehow missed it.\n\n4. Departure and arrival paths are drawn far above obstacles\nEvery published route and approach is designed to keep you at least 1,000 ft (often 2,000–5,000 ft) above the highest obstacle or terrain within 10–25 miles.\nIn mountainous areas the minimum altitudes are much higher (sometimes 10,000–15,000 ft above the peaks).\n\n5. In clouds or fog the plane is usually on autopilot following a pre-programmed path\nThat path was designed years ago by engineers who triple-checked it against every hill and building.\nThe autopilot flies it with far more precision than any human could.\n\n6. Real-life proof\nSince EGPWS became mandatory in the early 2000s, there has not been a single passenger jet accident worldwide caused by flying into terrain in clouds or fog on a properly flown approach or departure.\n\nSo when the clouds are thick and you can’t see anything outside, the plane is actually being guided by some of the most accurate and redundant navigation systems ever built.\nMountains and buildings are mapped, monitored, and avoided by multiple independent layers of technology and procedure.\n\nYou’re surrounded by invisible walls of safety that make it impossible to get anywhere near the ground unless something catastrophic and extraordinarily improbable happens to every system at once.\nIn clouds or fog, you’re often safer than on a clear day, because the automation and safeguards are doing all the work perfectly.\n\nFeel free to relax and enjoy the quiet grey view. Nothing out there can reach you.</string>
</resources>